<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928306667_507772_4251" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928306667_507772_4251"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" name="KeyboardFocusManager" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_391762_7057" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_391762_7057"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The KeyboardFocusManager is responsible for managing the active and focused
Windows, and the current focus owner. The focus owner is defined as the
Component in an application that will typically receive all KeyEvents
generated by the user. The focused Window is the Window that is, or
contains, the focus owner. Only a Frame or a Dialog can be the active
Window. The native windowing system may denote the active Window or its
children with special decorations, such as a highlighted title bar. The
active Window is always either the focused Window, or the first Frame or
Dialog that is an owner of the focused Window.
&lt;p&gt;
The KeyboardFocusManager is both a centralized location for client code to
query for the focus owner and initiate focus changes, and an event
dispatcher for all FocusEvents, WindowEvents related to focus, and
KeyEvents.
&lt;p&gt;
Some browsers partition applets in different code bases into separate
contexts, and establish walls between these contexts. In such a scenario,
there will be one KeyboardFocusManager per context. Other browsers place all
applets into the same context, implying that there will be only a single,
global KeyboardFocusManager for all applets. This behavior is
implementation-dependent. Consult your browser's documentation for more
information. No matter how many contexts there may be, however, there can
never be more than one focus owner, focused Window, or active Window, per
ClassLoader.
&lt;p&gt;
Please see
&lt;a href="http://java.sun.com/docs/books/tutorial/uiswing/misc/focus.html"&gt;
How to Use the Focus Subsystem&lt;/a&gt;,
a section in &lt;em&gt;The Java Tutorial&lt;/em&gt;, and the
&lt;a href="../../java/awt/doc-files/FocusSpec.html"&gt;Focus Specification&lt;/a&gt;
for more information.

@author David Mendenhall
@version 1.58, 05/05/04

@see Window
@see Frame
@see Dialog
@see java.awt.event.FocusEvent
@see java.awt.event.WindowEvent
@see java.awt.event.KeyEvent
@since 1.4
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" mode="s,e" name="KeyboardFocusManager" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_391762_7057" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_391762_7057"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" name="KeyboardFocusManager" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_391762_7057" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_391762_7057"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>