<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928318284_859694_12686" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928318284_859694_12686"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="TransferHandler" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_717489_10883" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_717489_10883"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class is used to handle the transfer of a &lt;code&gt;Transferable&lt;/code&gt;
to and from Swing components.  The &lt;code&gt;Transferable&lt;/code&gt; is used to
represent data that is exchanged via a cut, copy, or paste
to/from a clipboard.  It is also used in drag-and-drop operations
to represent a drag from a component, and a drop to a component.
Swing provides functionality that automatically supports cut, copy,
and paste keyboard bindings that use the functionality provided by
an implementation of this class.  Swing also provides functionality
that automatically supports drag and drop that uses the functionality
provided by an implementation of this class.  The Swing developer can
concentrate on specifying the semantics of a transfer primarily by setting
the &lt;code&gt;transferHandler&lt;/code&gt; property on a Swing component.
&lt;p&gt;
This class is implemented to provide a default behavior of transferring
a component property simply by specifying the name of the property in
the constructor.  For example, to transfer the foreground color from
one component to another either via the clipboard or a drag and drop operation
a &lt;code&gt;TransferHandler&lt;/code&gt; can be constructed with the string "foreground".  The
built in support will use the color returned by &lt;code&gt;getForeground&lt;/code&gt; as the source
of the transfer, and &lt;code&gt;setForeground&lt;/code&gt; for the target of a transfer.
&lt;p&gt;
Please see
&lt;a href="http://java.sun.com/docs/books/tutorial/uiswing/misc/dnd.html"&gt;
How to Use Drag and Drop and Data Transfer&lt;/a&gt;,
a section in &lt;em&gt;The Java Tutorial&lt;/em&gt;, for more information.


@author  Timothy Prinzing
@version 1.29 06/02/04
@since 1.4
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="TransferHandler" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_717489_10883" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_717489_10883"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="TransferHandler" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_717489_10883" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_717489_10883"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>