<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928305495_860335_3589"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="ICC_ColorSpace" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546549_719091_6445"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The ICC_ColorSpace class is an implementation of the abstract
ColorSpace class.  This representation of
device independent and device dependent color spaces is based on the
International Color Consortium Specification ICC.1:2001-12, File Format for
Color Profiles (see &lt;A href="http://www.color.org"&gt;http://www.color.org&lt;/A&gt;).
&lt;p&gt;
Typically, a Color or ColorModel would be associated with an ICC
Profile which is either an input, display, or output profile (see
the ICC specification).  There are other types of ICC Profiles, e.g.
abstract profiles, device link profiles, and named color profiles,
which do not contain information appropriate for representing the color
space of a color, image, or device (see ICC_Profile).
Attempting to create an ICC_ColorSpace object from an inappropriate ICC
Profile is an error.
&lt;p&gt;
ICC Profiles represent transformations from the color space of
the profile (e.g. a monitor) to a Profile Connection Space (PCS).
Profiles of interest for tagging images or colors have a
PCS which is one of the device independent
spaces (one CIEXYZ space and two CIELab spaces) defined in the
ICC Profile Format Specification.  Most profiles of interest
either have invertible transformations or explicitly specify
transformations going both directions.  Should an ICC_ColorSpace
object be used in a way requiring a conversion from PCS to
the profile's native space and there is inadequate data to
correctly perform the conversion, the ICC_ColorSpace object will
produce output in the specified type of color space (e.g. TYPE_RGB,
TYPE_CMYK, etc.), but the specific color values of the output data
will be undefined.
&lt;p&gt;
The details of this class are not important for simple applets,
which draw in a default color space or manipulate and display
imported images with a known color space.  At most, such applets
would need to get one of the default color spaces via
ColorSpace.getInstance().
&lt;p&gt;
@see ColorSpace
@see ICC_Profile
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="ICC_ColorSpace" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546549_719091_6445"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="ICC_ColorSpace" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546549_719091_6445"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>