<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928305495_307660_3591"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="ICC_Profile" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546549_402776_6447"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A representation of color profile data for device independent and
device dependent color spaces based on the International Color
Consortium Specification ICC.1:2001-12, File Format for Color Profiles,
(see &lt;A href="http://www.color.org"&gt; http://www.color.org&lt;/A&gt;).
&lt;p&gt;
An ICC_ColorSpace object can be constructed from an appropriate
ICC_Profile.
Typically, an ICC_ColorSpace would be associated with an ICC
Profile which is either an input, display, or output profile (see
the ICC specification).  There are also device link, abstract,
color space conversion, and named color profiles.  These are less
useful for tagging a color or image, but are useful for other
purposes (in particular device link profiles can provide improved
performance for converting from one device's color space to
another's).
&lt;p&gt;
ICC Profiles represent transformations from the color space of
the profile (e.g. a monitor) to a Profile Connection Space (PCS).
Profiles of interest for tagging images or colors have a PCS
which is one of the two specific device independent
spaces (one CIEXYZ space and one CIELab space) defined in the
ICC Profile Format Specification.  Most profiles of interest
either have invertible transformations or explicitly specify
transformations going both directions.
&lt;p&gt;
@version 10 Feb 1997
@see ICC_ColorSpace
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="ICC_Profile" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546549_402776_6447"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="ICC_Profile" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546549_402776_6447"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>