<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316271_748368_10647"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="Mixer" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_213641_9739"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A mixer is an audio device with one or more lines.  It need not be
designed for mixing audio signals.  A mixer that actually mixes audio
has multiple input (source) lines and at least one output (target) line.
The former are often instances of classes that implement
&lt;code&gt;{@link SourceDataLine}&lt;/code&gt;,
and the latter, &lt;code&gt;{@link TargetDataLine}&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;code&gt;{@link Port}&lt;/code&gt;
objects, too, are either source lines or target lines.
A mixer can accept prerecorded, loopable sound as input, by having
some of its source lines be instances of objects that implement the
&lt;code&gt;{@link Clip}&lt;/code&gt; interface.
&lt;p&gt;
Through methods of the &lt;code&gt;Line&lt;/code&gt; interface, which &lt;code&gt;Mixer&lt;/code&gt; extends,
a mixer might provide a set of controls that are global to the mixer.  For example,
the mixer can have a master gain control.  These global controls are distinct
from the controls belonging to each of the mixer's individual lines.
&lt;p&gt;
Some mixers, especially
those with internal digital mixing capabilities, may provide
additional capabilities by implementing the &lt;code&gt;DataLine&lt;/code&gt; interface.
&lt;p&gt;
A mixer can support synchronization of its lines.  When one line in
a synchronized group is started or stopped, the other lines in the group
automatically start or stop simultaneously with the explicitly affected one.

@author Kara Kytle
@version 1.31, 04/07/14
@since 1.3
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Mixer" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_213641_9739"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="Mixer" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_213641_9739"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>