<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928308650_569469_5439"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" name="SelectionKey" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546659_359793_7925"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A token representing the registration of a {@link SelectableChannel} with a
{@link Selector}.

&lt;p&gt; A selection key is created each time a channel is registered with a
selector.  A key remains valid until it is &lt;i&gt;cancelled&lt;/i&gt; by invoking its
{@link #cancel cancel} method, by closing its channel, or by closing its
selector.  Cancelling a key does not immediately remove it from its
selector; it is instead added to the selector's &lt;a
href="Selector.html#ks"&gt;&lt;i&gt;cancelled-key set&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for removal during the
next selection operation.  The validity of a key may be tested by invoking
its {@link #isValid isValid} method.

&lt;a name="opsets"&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A selection key contains two &lt;i&gt;operation sets&lt;/i&gt; represented as
integer values.  Each bit of an operation set denotes a category of
selectable operations that are supported by the key's channel.

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; The &lt;i&gt;interest set&lt;/i&gt; determines which operation categories will
be tested for readiness the next time one of the selector's selection
methods is invoked.  The interest set is initialized with the value given
when the key is created; it may later be changed via the {@link
#interestOps(int)} method. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; The &lt;i&gt;ready set&lt;/i&gt; identifies the operation categories for which
the key's channel has been detected to be ready by the key's selector.
The ready set is initialized to zero when the key is created; it may later
be updated by the selector during a selection operation, but it cannot be
updated directly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; That a selection key's ready set indicates that its channel is ready for
some operation category is a hint, but not a guarantee, that an operation in
such a category may be performed by a thread without causing the thread to
block.  A ready set is most likely to be accurate immediately after the
completion of a selection operation.  It is likely to be made inaccurate by
external events and by I/O operations that are invoked upon the
corresponding channel.

&lt;p&gt; This class defines all known operation-set bits, but precisely which
bits are supported by a given channel depends upon the type of the channel.
Each subclass of {@link SelectableChannel} defines an {@link
SelectableChannel#validOps() validOps()} method which returns a set
identifying just those operations that are supported by the channel.  An
attempt to set or test an operation-set bit that is not supported by a key's
channel will result in an appropriate run-time exception.

&lt;p&gt; It is often necessary to associate some application-specific data with a
selection key, for example an object that represents the state of a
higher-level protocol and handles readiness notifications in order to
implement that protocol.  Selection keys therefore support the
&lt;i&gt;attachment&lt;/i&gt; of a single arbitrary object to a key.  An object can be
attached via the {@link #attach attach} method and then later retrieved via
the {@link #attachment attachment} method.

&lt;p&gt; Selection keys are safe for use by multiple concurrent threads.  The
operations of reading and writing the interest set will, in general, be
synchronized with certain operations of the selector.  Exactly how this
synchronization is performed is implementation-dependent: In a naive
implementation, reading or writing the interest set may block indefinitely
if a selection operation is already in progress; in a high-performance
implementation, reading or writing the interest set may block briefly, if at
all.  In any case, a selection operation will always use the interest-set
value that was current at the moment that the operation began.  &lt;/p&gt;


@author Mark Reinhold
@author JSR-51 Expert Group
@version 1.24, 03/12/19
@since 1.4

@see SelectableChannel
@see Selector
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" mode="s,e" name="SelectionKey" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546659_359793_7925"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" name="SelectionKey" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546659_359793_7925"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>