<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316211_136315_10605"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="Encoding" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473548096_166818_20851"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The &lt;code&gt;Encoding&lt;/code&gt; class  names the  specific type of data representation
used for an audio stream.   The encoding includes aspects of the
sound format other than the number of channels, sample rate, sample size,
frame rate, frame size, and byte order.
&lt;p&gt;
One ubiquitous type of audio encoding is pulse-code modulation (PCM),
which is simply a linear (proportional) representation of the sound
waveform.  With PCM, the number stored in each sample is proportional
to the instantaneous amplitude of the sound pressure at that point in
time.  The numbers are frequently signed or unsigned integers.
Besides PCM, other encodings include mu-law and a-law, which are nonlinear
mappings of the sound amplitude that are often used for recording speech.
&lt;p&gt;
You can use a predefined encoding by referring to one of the static
objects created by this class, such as PCM_SIGNED or
PCM_UNSIGNED.  Service providers can create new encodings, such as
compressed audio formats or floating-point PCM samples, and make
these available through the &lt;code&gt;{@link AudioSystem}&lt;/code&gt; class.
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;Encoding&lt;/code&gt; class is static, so that all
&lt;code&gt;AudioFormat&lt;/code&gt; objects that have the same encoding will refer
to the same object (rather than different instances of the same class).
This allows matches to be made by checking that two format's encodings
are equal.

@see AudioFormat
@see javax.sound.sampled.spi.FormatConversionProvider

@author Kara Kytle
@version 1.35 04/03/15
@since 1.3
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Encoding" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473548096_166818_20851"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="Encoding" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473548096_166818_20851"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>