<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315670_22568_10156" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928315670_22568_10156"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="JobPriority" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_766906_9353" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_766906_9353"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Class JobPriority is an integer valued printing attribute class that
specifies a print job's priority.
&lt;P&gt;
If a JobPriority attribute is specified for a Print Job, it specifies a
priority for scheduling the job. A higher value specifies a higher priority.
The value 1 indicates the lowest possible priority. The value 100 indicates
the highest possible priority. Among those jobs that are ready to print, a
printer must print all jobs with a priority value of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt; before printing
those with a priority value of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt;-1 for all &lt;I&gt;n.&lt;/I&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
If the client does not specify a JobPriority attribute for a Print Job and
the printer does support the JobPriority attribute, the printer must use an
implementation-defined default JobPriority value.
&lt;P&gt;
The client can always specify any job priority value from 1 to 100 for a job.
However, a Print Service instance may support fewer than 100 different
job priority levels. If this is the case, the Print Service instance
automatically maps the client-specified job priority value to one of the
supported job priority levels, dividing the 100 job priority values equally
among the available job priority levels.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The integer value gives the IPP integer value. The
category name returned by &lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; gives the IPP attribute
name.
&lt;P&gt;

@author  Alan Kaminsky
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="JobPriority" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_766906_9353" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_766906_9353"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="JobPriority" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_766906_9353" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_766906_9353"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>