<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928309281_852493_5960"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="AlgorithmParameterGenerator" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_83621_8417"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The &lt;code&gt;AlgorithmParameterGenerator&lt;/code&gt; class is used to generate a
set of
parameters to be used with a certain algorithm. Parameter generators
are constructed using the &lt;code&gt;getInstance&lt;/code&gt; factory methods
(static methods that return instances of a given class).

&lt;P&gt;The object that will generate the parameters can be initialized
in two different ways: in an algorithm-independent manner, or in an
algorithm-specific manner:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The algorithm-independent approach uses the fact that all parameter
generators share the concept of a "size" and a
source of randomness. The measure of size is universally shared
by all algorithm parameters, though it is interpreted differently
for different algorithms. For example, in the case of parameters for
the &lt;i&gt;DSA&lt;/i&gt; algorithm, "size" corresponds to the size
of the prime modulus (in bits).
When using this approach, algorithm-specific parameter generation
values - if any - default to some standard values, unless they can be
derived from the specified size.&lt;P&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The other approach initializes a parameter generator object
using algorithm-specific semantics, which are represented by a set of
algorithm-specific parameter generation values. To generate
Diffie-Hellman system parameters, for example, the parameter generation
values usually
consist of the size of the prime modulus and the size of the
random exponent, both specified in number of bits.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;P&gt;In case the client does not explicitly initialize the
AlgorithmParameterGenerator
(via a call to an &lt;code&gt;init&lt;/code&gt; method), each provider must supply (and
document) a default initialization. For example, the Sun provider uses a
default modulus prime size of 1024 bits for the generation of DSA
parameters.

@author Jan Luehe

@version 1.40, 12/19/03

@see AlgorithmParameters
@see java.security.spec.AlgorithmParameterSpec

@since 1.2
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="AlgorithmParameterGenerator" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_83621_8417"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="AlgorithmParameterGenerator" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_83621_8417"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>