<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928307308_731446_4634" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928307308_731446_4634"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="HandleTable" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473547487_811522_17631" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473547487_811522_17631"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Unsynchronized table which tracks wire handle to object mappings, as
well as ClassNotFoundExceptions associated with deserialized objects.
This class implements an exception-propagation algorithm for
determining which objects should have ClassNotFoundExceptions associated
with them, taking into account cycles and discontinuities (e.g., skipped
fields) in the object graph.

&lt;p&gt;General use of the table is as follows: during deserialization, a
given object is first assigned a handle by calling the assign method.
This method leaves the assigned handle in an "open" state, wherein
dependencies on the exception status of other handles can be registered
by calling the markDependency method, or an exception can be directly
associated with the handle by calling markException.  When a handle is
tagged with an exception, the HandleTable assumes responsibility for
propagating the exception to any other objects which depend
(transitively) on the exception-tagged object.

&lt;p&gt;Once all exception information/dependencies for the handle have been
registered, the handle should be "closed" by calling the finish method
on it.  The act of finishing a handle allows the exception propagation
algorithm to aggressively prune dependency links, lessening the
performance/memory impact of exception tracking.

&lt;p&gt;Note that the exception propagation algorithm used depends on handles
being assigned/finished in LIFO order; however, for simplicity as well
as memory conservation, it does not enforce this constraint.
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="HandleTable" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473547487_811522_17631" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473547487_811522_17631"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="HandleTable" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473547487_811522_17631" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473547487_811522_17631"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>