<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928318183_557130_12577"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="KeyStroke" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_308362_10799"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A KeyStroke represents a key action on the keyboard, or equivalent input
device. KeyStrokes can correspond to only a press or release of a particular
key, just as KEY_PRESSED and KEY_RELEASED KeyEvents do; alternately, they
can correspond to typing a specific Java character, just as KEY_TYPED
KeyEvents do. In all cases, KeyStrokes can specify modifiers (alt, shift,
control, meta, or a combination thereof) which must be present during the
action for an exact match.
&lt;p&gt;
KeyStrokes are used to define high-level (semantic) action events. Instead
of trapping every keystroke and throwing away the ones you are not
interested in, those keystrokes you care about automatically initiate
actions on the Components with which they are registered.
&lt;p&gt;
KeyStrokes are immutable, and are intended to be unique. Client code cannot
create a KeyStroke; a variant of &lt;code&gt;getKeyStroke&lt;/code&gt; must be used
instead. These factory methods allow the KeyStroke implementation to cache
and share instances efficiently.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt;
Serialized objects of this class will not be compatible with
future Swing releases. The current serialization support is
appropriate for short term storage or RMI between applications running
the same version of Swing.  As of 1.4, support for long term storage
of all JavaBeans&lt;sup&gt;&lt;font size="-2"&gt;TM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
has been added to the &lt;code&gt;java.beans&lt;/code&gt; package.
Please see {@link java.beans.XMLEncoder}.

@see javax.swing.text.Keymap
@see #getKeyStroke

@version 1.49, 05/18/04
@author Arnaud Weber
@author David Mendenhall
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="KeyStroke" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_308362_10799"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="KeyStroke" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_308362_10799"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>