<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928308339_263206_5273"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="InetAddress" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546643_279990_7769"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class represents an Internet Protocol (IP) address.

&lt;p&gt; An IP address is either a 32-bit or 128-bit unsigned number
used by IP, a lower-level protocol on which protocols like UDP and
TCP are built. The IP address architecture is defined by &lt;a
href="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc790.txt"&gt;&lt;i&gt;RFC&amp;nbsp;790:
Assigned Numbers&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
href="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc1918.txt"&gt; &lt;i&gt;RFC&amp;nbsp;1918:
Address Allocation for Private Internets&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
href="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2365.txt"&gt;&lt;i&gt;RFC&amp;nbsp;2365:
Administratively Scoped IP Multicast&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a
href="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2373.txt"&gt;&lt;i&gt;RFC&amp;nbsp;2373: IP
Version 6 Addressing Architecture&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. An instance of an
InetAddress consists of an IP address and possibly its
corresponding host name (depending on whether it is constructed
with a host name or whether it has already done reverse host name
resolution).

&lt;h4&gt; Address types &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;table cellspacing=2 summary="Description of unicast and multicast address types"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th valign=top&gt;&lt;i&gt;unicast&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An identifier for a single interface. A packet sent to
a unicast address is delivered to the interface identified by
that address.

&lt;p&gt; The Unspecified Address -- Also called anylocal or wildcard
address. It must never be assigned to any node. It indicates the
absence of an address. One example of its use is as the target of
bind, which allows a server to accept a client connection on any
interface, in case the server host has multiple interfaces.

&lt;p&gt; The &lt;i&gt;unspecified&lt;/i&gt; address must not be used as
the destination address of an IP packet.

&lt;p&gt; The &lt;i&gt;Loopback&lt;/i&gt; Addresses -- This is the address
assigned to the loopback interface. Anything sent to this
IP address loops around and becomes IP input on the local
host. This address is often used when testing a
client.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th valign=top&gt;&lt;i&gt;multicast&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An identifier for a set of interfaces (typically belonging
to different nodes). A packet sent to a multicast address is
delivered to all interfaces identified by that address.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; IP address scope &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;Link-local&lt;/i&gt; addresses are designed to be used for addressing
on a single link for purposes such as auto-address configuration,
neighbor discovery, or when no routers are present.

&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;Site-local&lt;/i&gt; addresses are designed to be used for addressing
inside of a site without the need for a global prefix.

&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;Global&lt;/i&gt; addresses are unique across the internet.

&lt;h4&gt; Textual representation of IP addresses &lt;/h4&gt;

The textual representation of an IP address is address family specific.

&lt;p&gt;

For IPv4 address format, please refer to &lt;A
HREF="Inet4Address.html#format"&gt;Inet4Address#format&lt;/A&gt;; For IPv6
address format, please refer to &lt;A
HREF="Inet6Address.html#format"&gt;Inet6Address#format&lt;/A&gt;.

&lt;h4&gt; Host Name Resolution &lt;/h4&gt;

Host name-to-IP address &lt;i&gt;resolution&lt;/i&gt; is accomplished through
the use of a combination of local machine configuration information
and network naming services such as the Domain Name System (DNS)
and Network Information Service(NIS). The particular naming
services(s) being used is by default the local machine configured
one. For any host name, its corresponding IP address is returned.

&lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;Reverse name resolution&lt;/i&gt; means that for any IP address,
the host associated with the IP address is returned.

&lt;p&gt; The InetAddress class provides methods to resolve host names to
their IP addresses and vise versa.

&lt;h4&gt; InetAddress Caching &lt;/h4&gt;

The InetAddress class has a cache to store successful as well as
unsuccessful host name resolutions. The positive caching is there
to guard against DNS spoofing attacks; while the negative caching
is used to improve performance.

&lt;p&gt; By default, the result of positive host name resolutions are
cached forever, because there is no general rule to decide when it
is safe to remove cache entries. The result of unsuccessful host
name resolution is cached for a very short period of time (10
seconds) to improve performance.

&lt;p&gt; Under certain circumstances where it can be determined that DNS
spoofing attacks are not possible, a Java security property can be
set to a different Time-to-live (TTL) value for positive
caching. Likewise, a system admin can configure a different
negative caching TTL value when needed.

&lt;p&gt; Two Java security properties control the TTL values used for
positive and negative host name resolution caching:

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;networkaddress.cache.ttl&lt;/b&gt; (default: -1)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Indicates the caching policy for successful name lookups from
the name service. The value is specified as as integer to indicate
the number of seconds to cache the successful lookup.
&lt;p&gt;
A value of -1 indicates "cache forever".
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;networkaddress.cache.negative.ttl&lt;/b&gt; (default: 10)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Indicates the caching policy for un-successful name lookups
from the name service. The value is specified as as integer to
indicate the number of seconds to cache the failure for
un-successful lookups.
&lt;p&gt;
A value of 0 indicates "never cache".
A value of -1 indicates "cache forever".
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

@author  Chris Warth
@version 1.109, 04/19/04
@see     java.net.InetAddress#getByAddress(byte[])
@see     java.net.InetAddress#getByAddress(java.lang.String, byte[])
@see     java.net.InetAddress#getAllByName(java.lang.String)
@see     java.net.InetAddress#getByName(java.lang.String)
@see     java.net.InetAddress#getLocalHost()
@since JDK1.0
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="InetAddress" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546643_279990_7769"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="InetAddress" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546643_279990_7769"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>