<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928306046_651541_3934"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="ConvolveOp" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_588906_6769"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class implements a convolution from the source
to the destination.
Convolution using a convolution kernel is a spatial operation that
computes the output pixel from an input pixel by multiplying the kernel
with the surround of the input pixel.
This allows the output pixel to be affected by the immediate neighborhood
in a way that can be mathematically specified with a kernel.
&lt;p&gt;
This class operates with BufferedImage data in which color components are
premultiplied with the alpha component.  If the Source BufferedImage has
an alpha component, and the color components are not premultiplied with
the alpha component, then the data are premultiplied before being
convolved.  If the Destination has color components which are not
premultiplied, then alpha is divided out before storing into the
Destination (if alpha is 0, the color components are set to 0).  If the
Destination has no alpha component, then the resulting alpha is discarded
after first dividing it out of the color components.
&lt;p&gt;
Rasters are treated as having no alpha channel.  If the above treatment
of the alpha channel in BufferedImages is not desired, it may be avoided
by getting the Raster of a source BufferedImage and using the filter method
of this class which works with Rasters.
&lt;p&gt;
If a RenderingHints object is specified in the constructor, the
color rendering hint and the dithering hint may be used when color
conversion is required.
&lt;p&gt;
Note that the Source and the Destination may not be the same object.
@version 10 Feb 1997
@see Kernel
@see java.awt.RenderingHints#KEY_COLOR_RENDERING
@see java.awt.RenderingHints#KEY_DITHERING
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="ConvolveOp" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_588906_6769"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="ConvolveOp" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_588906_6769"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>