<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316010_846977_10433"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="KerberosTicket" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_774235_9597"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class encapsulates a Kerberos ticket and associated
information as viewed from the client's point of view. It captures all
information that the Key Distribution Center (KDC) sends to the client
in the reply message KDC-REP defined in the Kerberos Protocol
Specification (&lt;a href=http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc1510.txt&gt;RFC 1510&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;p&gt;
All Kerberos JAAS login modules that authenticate a user to a KDC should
use this class. Where available, the login module might even read this
information from a ticket cache in the operating system instead of
directly communicating with the KDC. During the commit phase of the JAAS
authentication process, the JAAS login module should instantiate this
class and store the instance in the private credential set of a
{@link javax.security.auth.Subject Subject}.&lt;p&gt;

It might be necessary for the application to be granted a
{@link javax.security.auth.PrivateCredentialPermission
PrivateCredentialPermission} if it needs to access a KerberosTicket
instance from a Subject. This permission is not needed when the
application depends on the default JGSS Kerberos mechanism to access the
KerberosTicket. In that case, however, the application will need an
appropriate
{@link javax.security.auth.kerberos.ServicePermission ServicePermission}.
&lt;p&gt;
Note that this class is applicable to both ticket granting tickets and
other regular service tickets. A ticket granting ticket is just a
special case of a more generalized service ticket.

@see javax.security.auth.Subject
@see javax.security.auth.PrivateCredentialPermission
@see javax.security.auth.login.LoginContext
@see org.ietf.jgss.GSSCredential
@see org.ietf.jgss.GSSManager

@author Mayank Upadhyay
@version 1.16, 06/02/04
@since 1.4
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="KerberosTicket" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_774235_9597"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="KerberosTicket" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_774235_9597"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>