<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316191_913760_10580"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="Soundbank" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_147853_9685"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A &lt;code&gt;Soundbank&lt;/code&gt; contains a set of &lt;code&gt;Instruments&lt;/code&gt;
that can be loaded into a &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt;.
Note that a Java Sound &lt;code&gt;Soundbank&lt;/code&gt; is different from a MIDI bank.
MIDI permits up to 16383 banks, each containing up to 128 instruments
(also sometimes called programs, patches, or timbres).
However, a &lt;code&gt;Soundbank&lt;/code&gt; can contain 16383 times 128 instruments,
because the instruments within a &lt;code&gt;Soundbank&lt;/code&gt; are indexed by both
a MIDI program number and a MIDI bank number (via a &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt;
object). Thus, a &lt;code&gt;Soundbank&lt;/code&gt; can be thought of as a collection
of MIDI banks.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Soundbank&lt;/code&gt; includes methods that return &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;
objects containing the sound bank's name, manufacturer, version number, and
description.  The precise content and format of these strings is left
to the implementor.
&lt;p&gt;
Different synthesizers use a variety of synthesis techniques.  A common
one is wavetable synthesis, in which a segment of recorded sound is
played back, often with looping and pitch change.  The Downloadable Sound
(DLS) format uses segments of recorded sound, as does the Headspace Engine.
&lt;code&gt;Soundbanks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Instruments&lt;/code&gt; that are based on
wavetable synthesis (or other uses of stored sound recordings) should
typically implement the &lt;code&gt;getResources()&lt;/code&gt;
method to provide access to these recorded segments.  This is optional,
however; the method can return an zero-length array if the synthesis technique
doesn't use sampled sound (FM synthesis and physical modeling are examples
of such techniques), or if it does but the implementor chooses not to make the
samples accessible.

@see Synthesizer#getDefaultSoundbank
@see Synthesizer#isSoundbankSupported
@see Synthesizer#loadInstruments(Soundbank, Patch[])
@see Patch
@see Instrument
@see SoundbankResource

@version 1.24, 03/12/19
@author David Rivas
@author Kara Kytle
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Soundbank" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_147853_9685"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="Soundbank" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_147853_9685"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>