<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316000_406403_10408" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928316000_406403_10408"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="CallbackHandler" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_150058_9571" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_150058_9571"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">&lt;p&gt; An application implements a &lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt; and passes
it to underlying security services so that they may interact with
the application to retrieve specific authentication data,
such as usernames and passwords, or to display certain information,
such as error and warning messages.

&lt;p&gt; CallbackHandlers are implemented in an application-dependent fashion.
For example, implementations for an application with a graphical user
interface (GUI) may pop up windows to prompt for requested information
or to display error messages.  An implementation may also choose to obtain
requested information from an alternate source without asking the end user.

&lt;p&gt; Underlying security services make requests for different types
of information by passing individual Callbacks to the
&lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt;.  The &lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt;
implementation decides how to retrieve and display information
depending on the Callbacks passed to it.  For example,
if the underlying service needs a username and password to
authenticate a user, it uses a &lt;code&gt;NameCallback&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;PasswordCallback&lt;/code&gt;.  The &lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt;
can then choose to prompt for a username and password serially,
or to prompt for both in a single window.

&lt;p&gt; A default &lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt; class implementation
may be specified in the &lt;i&gt;auth.login.defaultCallbackHandler&lt;/i&gt;
security property.  The security property can be set
in the Java security properties file located in the file named
&lt;JAVA_HOME&gt;/lib/security/java.security, where &lt;JAVA_HOME&gt;
refers to the directory where the JDK was installed.

&lt;p&gt; If the security property is set to the fully qualified name of a
&lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt; implementation class,
then a &lt;code&gt;LoginContext&lt;/code&gt; will load the specified
&lt;code&gt;CallbackHandler&lt;/code&gt; and pass it to the underlying LoginModules.
The &lt;code&gt;LoginContext&lt;/code&gt; only loads the default handler
if it was not provided one.

&lt;p&gt; All default handler implementations must provide a public
zero-argument constructor.

@version 1.17, 06/28/04
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" mode="s,e" name="CallbackHandler" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_150058_9571" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_150058_9571"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="CallbackHandler" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_150058_9571" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_150058_9571"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>