<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315720_349922_10195"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="OrientationRequested" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_488828_9387"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Class OrientationRequested is a printing attribute class, an enumeration,
that indicates the desired orientation for printed print-stream pages; it
does not describe the orientation of the client-supplied print-stream
pages.
&lt;P&gt;
For some document formats (such as &lt;CODE&gt;"application/postscript"&lt;/CODE&gt;),
the desired orientation of the print-stream pages is specified within the
document data. This information is generated by a device driver prior to
the submission of the print job. Other document formats (such as
&lt;CODE&gt;"text/plain"&lt;/CODE&gt;) do not include the notion of desired orientation
within the document data. In the latter case it is possible for the printer
to bind the desired orientation to the document data after it has been
submitted. It is expected that a printer would only support the
OrientationRequested attribute for some document formats (e.g.,
&lt;CODE&gt;"text/plain"&lt;/CODE&gt; or &lt;CODE&gt;"text/html"&lt;/CODE&gt;) but not others (e.g.
&lt;CODE&gt;"application/postscript"&lt;/CODE&gt;). This is no different from any other
job template attribute, since a print job can always impose constraints
among the values of different job template attributes.
However, a special mention
is made here since it is very likely that a printer will support the
OrientationRequested attribute for only a subset of the supported document
formats.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The category name returned by
&lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; is the IPP attribute name.  The enumeration's
integer value is the IPP enum value.  The &lt;code&gt;toString()&lt;/code&gt; method
returns the IPP string representation of the attribute value.
&lt;P&gt;

@author  Alan Kaminsky
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="OrientationRequested" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_488828_9387"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="OrientationRequested" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_488828_9387"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>