<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316191_766189_10584" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928316191_766189_10584"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="Synthesizer" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_153094_9689" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_153094_9689"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt; generates sound.  This usually happens when one of
the &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt;'s {@link MidiChannel} objects receives a
{@link MidiChannel#noteOn(int, int) noteOn} message, either
directly or via the &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt; object.
Many &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt;s support &lt;code&gt;Receivers&lt;/code&gt;, through which
MIDI events can be delivered to the &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt;.
In such cases, the &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt; typically responds by sending
a corresponding message to the appropriate &lt;code&gt;MidiChannel&lt;/code&gt;, or by
processing the event itself if the event isn't one of the MIDI channel
messages.
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt; interface includes methods for loading and
unloading instruments from soundbanks.  An instrument is a specification for synthesizing a
certain type of sound, whether that sound emulates a traditional instrument or is
some kind of sound effect or other imaginary sound. A soundbank is a collection of instruments, organized
by bank and program number (via the instrument's &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt; object).
Different &lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt; classes might implement different sound-synthesis
techniques, meaning that some instruments and not others might be compatible with a
given synthesizer.
Also, synthesizers may have a limited amount of memory for instruments, meaning
that not every soundbank and instrument can be used by every synthesizer, even if
the synthesis technique is compatible.
To see whether the instruments from
a certain soundbank can be played by a given synthesizer, invoke the
{@link #isSoundbankSupported(Soundbank) isSoundbankSupported} method of
&lt;code&gt;Synthesizer&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;
"Loading" an instrument means that that instrument becomes available for
synthesizing notes.  The instrument is loaded into the bank and
program location specified by its &lt;code&gt;Patch&lt;/code&gt; object.  Loading does
not necessarily mean that subsequently played notes will immediately have
the sound of this newly loaded instrument.  For the instrument to play notes,
one of the synthesizer's &lt;code&gt;MidiChannel&lt;/code&gt; objects must receive (or have received)
a program-change message that causes that particular instrument's
bank and program number to be selected.

@see MidiSystem#getSynthesizer
@see Soundbank
@see Instrument
@see MidiChannel#programChange(int, int)
@see Receiver
@see Transmitter
@see MidiDevice

@version 1.27, 03/12/19
@author Kara Kytle
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Synthesizer" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_153094_9689" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_153094_9689"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="Synthesizer" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_153094_9689" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_153094_9689"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>