<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315970_204877_10350"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="MimeType" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_149723_9521"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Class MimeType encapsulates a Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions (MIME)
media type as defined in &lt;A HREF="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2045.txt"&gt;RFC
2045&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A HREF="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2046.txt"&gt;RFC 2046&lt;/A&gt;. A
MIME type object is part of a {@link DocFlavor DocFlavor} object and
specifies the format of the print data.
&lt;P&gt;
Class MimeType is similar to the like-named
class in package {@link java.awt.datatransfer java.awt.datatransfer}. Class
java.awt.datatransfer.MimeType is not used in the Jini Print Service API
for two reasons:
&lt;OL TYPE=1&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
Since not all Java profiles include the AWT, the Jini Print Service should
not depend on an AWT class.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
The implementation of class java.awt.datatransfer.MimeType does not
guarantee
that equivalent MIME types will have the same serialized representation.
Thus, since the Jini Lookup Service (JLUS) matches service attributes based
on equality of serialized representations, JLUS searches involving MIME
types encapsulated in class java.awt.datatransfer.MimeType may incorrectly
fail to match.
&lt;/OL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Class MimeType's serialized representation is based on the following
canonical form of a MIME type string. Thus, two MIME types that are not
identical but that are equivalent (that have the same canonical form) will
be considered equal by the JLUS's matching algorithm.
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt; The media type, media subtype, and parameters are retained, but all
comments and whitespace characters are discarded.
&lt;LI&gt; The media type, media subtype, and parameter names are converted to
lowercase.
&lt;LI&gt; The parameter values retain their original case, except a charset
parameter value for a text media type is converted to lowercase.
&lt;LI&gt; Quote characters surrounding parameter values are removed.
&lt;LI&gt; Quoting backslash characters inside parameter values are removed.
&lt;LI&gt; The parameters are arranged in ascending order of parameter name.
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;

@author  Alan Kaminsky
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="MimeType" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_149723_9521"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="MimeType" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_149723_9521"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>