<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315670_912596_10164" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928315670_912596_10164"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="JobStateReason" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_151389_9361" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_151389_9361"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Class JobStateReason is a printing attribute class, an enumeration, that
provides additional information about the job's current state, i.e.,
information that augments the value of the job's {@link JobState JobState}
attribute. Class JobStateReason defines standard job state reason values. A
Print Service implementation only needs to report those job state
reasons which are appropriate for the particular implementation; it does not
have to report every defined job state reason.
&lt;P&gt;
Instances of JobStateReason do not appear in a Print Job's attribute set
directly. Rather, a {@link JobStateReasons JobStateReasons} attribute appears
in the Print Job's attribute set. The {@link JobStateReasons JobStateReasons}
attribute contains zero, one, or more than one JobStateReason objects which
pertain to the Print Job's status. The printer adds a JobStateReason object
to the Print Job's {@link JobStateReasons JobStateReasons} attribute when the
corresponding condition becomes true of the Print Job, and the printer
removes the JobStateReason object again when the corresponding condition
becomes false, regardless of whether the Print Job's overall {@link JobState
JobState} also changed.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The category name returned by
&lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; is the IPP attribute name.  The enumeration's
integer value is the IPP enum value.  The &lt;code&gt;toString()&lt;/code&gt; method
returns the IPP string representation of the attribute value.
&lt;P&gt;

@author  Alan Kaminsky
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="JobStateReason" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_151389_9361" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_151389_9361"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="JobStateReason" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_151389_9361" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_151389_9361"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>