<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928314919_290179_9325"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="ModelMBeanNotificationBroadcaster" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928314919_307512_9323"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This interface must be implemented by the ModelMBeans. An implementation of this interface
must be shipped with every JMX Agent.
&lt;P&gt;
Java resources wishing to be manageable instantiate the ModelMBean using the MBeanServer's
createMBean method.  The resource then sets the ModelMBeanInfo (with Descriptors) for the ModelMBean
instance. The attributes and operations exposed via the ModelMBeanInfo for the ModelMBean are accessible
from MBeans, connectors/adaptors like other MBeans. Through the ModelMBeanInfo Descriptors, values and methods in
the managed application can be defined and mapped to attributes and operations of the ModelMBean.
This mapping can be defined during development in an XML formatted file or dynamically and
programmatically at runtime.
&lt;P&gt;
Every ModelMBean which is instantiated in the MBeanServer becomes manageable:
its attributes and operations
become remotely accessible through the connectors/adaptors connected to that MBeanServer.
A Java object cannot be registered in the MBeanServer unless it is a JMX compliant MBean.
By instantiating a ModelMBean, resources are guaranteed that the MBean is valid.
&lt;P&gt;
MBeanException and RuntimeOperationsException must be thrown on every public method.  This allows
for wrapping exceptions from distributed communications (RMI, EJB, etc.).  These exceptions do
not have to be thrown by the implementation except in the scenarios described in the specification
and javadoc.

@since 1.5
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="ModelMBeanNotificationBroadcaster" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928314919_307512_9323"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="ModelMBeanNotificationBroadcaster" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928314919_307512_9323"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>