<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928316972_699187_10761"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="PooledConnection" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546753_1680_9759"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">An object that provides hooks for connection pool management.
A &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; object
represents a physical connection to a data source.  The connection
can be recycled rather than being closed when an application is
finished with it, thus reducing the number of connections that
need to be made.
&lt;P&gt;
An application programmer does not use the &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt;
interface directly; rather, it is used by a middle tier infrastructure
that manages the pooling of connections.
&lt;P&gt;
When an application calls the method &lt;code&gt;DataSource.getConnection&lt;/code&gt;,
it gets back a &lt;code&gt;Connection&lt;/code&gt; object.  If connection pooling is
being done, that &lt;code&gt;Connection&lt;/code&gt; object is actually a handle to
a &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; object, which is a physical connection.
&lt;P&gt;
The connection pool manager, typically the application server, maintains
a pool of &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; objects.  If there is a
&lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; object available in the pool, the
connection pool manager returns a &lt;code&gt;Connection&lt;/code&gt; object that
is a handle to that physical connection.
If no &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; object is available, the
connection pool manager calls the &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt;
method &lt;code&gt;getConnection&lt;/code&gt; to create a new physical connection and
returns a handle to it.
&lt;P&gt;
When an application closes a connection, it calls the &lt;code&gt;Connection&lt;/code&gt;
method &lt;code&gt;close&lt;/code&gt;. When connection pooling is being done,
the connection pool manager is notified because it has registered itself as
a &lt;code&gt;ConnectionEventListener&lt;/code&gt; object using the
&lt;code&gt;ConnectionPool&lt;/code&gt; method &lt;code&gt;addConnectionEventListener&lt;/code&gt;.
The connection pool manager deactivates the handle to
the &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; object and  returns the
&lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; object to the pool of connections so that
it can be used again.  Thus, when an application closes its connection,
the underlying physical connection is recycled rather than being closed.
&lt;P&gt;
The physical connection is not closed until the connection pool manager
calls the &lt;code&gt;PooledConnection&lt;/code&gt; method &lt;code&gt;close&lt;/code&gt;.
This method is generally called to have an orderly shutdown of the server or
if a fatal error has made the connection unusable.

@since 1.4
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="PooledConnection" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546753_1680_9759"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="PooledConnection" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546753_1680_9759"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>