<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928306477_434766_4212" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928306477_434766_4212"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" name="Graphics" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_175096_7021" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_175096_7021"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The &lt;code&gt;Graphics&lt;/code&gt; class is the abstract base class for
all graphics contexts that allow an application to draw onto
components that are realized on various devices, as well as
onto off-screen images.
&lt;p&gt;
A &lt;code&gt;Graphics&lt;/code&gt; object encapsulates state information needed
for the basic rendering operations that Java supports.  This
state information includes the following properties:
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Component&lt;/code&gt; object on which to draw.
&lt;li&gt;A translation origin for rendering and clipping coordinates.
&lt;li&gt;The current clip.
&lt;li&gt;The current color.
&lt;li&gt;The current font.
&lt;li&gt;The current logical pixel operation function (XOR or Paint).
&lt;li&gt;The current XOR alternation color
(see {@link Graphics#setXORMode}).
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Coordinates are infinitely thin and lie between the pixels of the
output device.
Operations that draw the outline of a figure operate by traversing
an infinitely thin path between pixels with a pixel-sized pen that hangs
down and to the right of the anchor point on the path.
Operations that fill a figure operate by filling the interior
of that infinitely thin path.
Operations that render horizontal text render the ascending
portion of character glyphs entirely above the baseline coordinate.
&lt;p&gt;
The graphics pen hangs down and to the right from the path it traverses.
This has the following implications:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you draw a figure that covers a given rectangle, that
figure occupies one extra row of pixels on the right and bottom edges
as compared to filling a figure that is bounded by that same rectangle.
&lt;li&gt;If you draw a horizontal line along the same &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt; coordinate as
the baseline of a line of text, that line is drawn entirely below
the text, except for any descenders.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All coordinates that appear as arguments to the methods of this
&lt;code&gt;Graphics&lt;/code&gt; object are considered relative to the
translation origin of this &lt;code&gt;Graphics&lt;/code&gt; object prior to
the invocation of the method.
&lt;p&gt;
All rendering operations modify only pixels which lie within the
area bounded by the current clip, which is specified by a {@link Shape}
in user space and is controlled by the program using the
&lt;code&gt;Graphics&lt;/code&gt; object.  This &lt;i&gt;user clip&lt;/i&gt;
is transformed into device space and combined with the
&lt;i&gt;device clip&lt;/i&gt;, which is defined by the visibility of windows and
device extents.  The combination of the user clip and device clip
defines the &lt;i&gt;composite clip&lt;/i&gt;, which determines the final clipping
region.  The user clip cannot be modified by the rendering
system to reflect the resulting composite clip. The user clip can only
be changed through the &lt;code&gt;setClip&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;clipRect&lt;/code&gt;
methods.
All drawing or writing is done in the current color,
using the current paint mode, and in the current font.

@version 	1.69, 05/18/04
@author 	Sami Shaio
@author 	Arthur van Hoff
@see     java.awt.Component
@see     java.awt.Graphics#clipRect(int, int, int, int)
@see     java.awt.Graphics#setColor(java.awt.Color)
@see     java.awt.Graphics#setPaintMode()
@see     java.awt.Graphics#setXORMode(java.awt.Color)
@see     java.awt.Graphics#setFont(java.awt.Font)
@since       JDK1.0
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Graphics" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_175096_7021" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_175096_7021"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" name="Graphics" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_175096_7021" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_175096_7021"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>