<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315830_107485_10331" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928315830_107485_10331"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="Doc" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_544729_9513" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_544729_9513"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Interface Doc specifies the interface for an object that supplies one piece
of print data for a Print Job. "Doc" is a short, easy-to-pronounce term
that means "a piece of print data." The client passes to the Print Job an
object that implements interface Doc, and the Print Job calls methods on
that object to obtain the print data. The Doc interface lets a Print Job:
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
Determine the format, or "doc flavor" (class {@link DocFlavor DocFlavor}),
in which the print data is available. A doc flavor designates the print
data format (a MIME type) and the representation class of the object
from which the print data comes.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
Obtain the print data representation object, which is an instance of the
doc flavor's representation class. The Print Job can then obtain the actual
print data from the representation object.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
Obtain the printing attributes that specify additional characteristics of
the doc or that specify processing instructions to be applied to the doc.
Printing attributes are defined in package {@link javax.print.attribute
javax.print.attribute}. The doc returns its printing attributes stored in
an {@link javax.print.attribute.DocAttributeSet javax.print.attribute.DocAttributeSet}.
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Each method in an implementation of interface Doc is permitted always to
return the same object each time the method is called.
This has implications
for a Print Job or other caller of a doc object whose print data
representation object "consumes" the print data as the caller obtains the
print data, such as a print data representation object which is a stream.
Once the Print Job has called {@link #getPrintData()
&lt;CODE&gt;getPrintData()&lt;/CODE&gt;} and obtained the stream, any further calls to
{@link #getPrintData() &lt;CODE&gt;getPrintData()&lt;/CODE&gt;} will return the same
stream object upon which reading may already be in progress, &lt;I&gt;not&lt;/I&gt; a new
stream object that will re-read the print data from the beginning. Specifying
a doc object to behave this way simplifies the implementation of doc objects,
and is justified on the grounds that a particular doc is intended to convey
print data only to one Print Job, not to several different Print Jobs. (To
convey the same print data to several different Print Jobs, you have to
create several different doc objects on top of the same print data source.)
&lt;P&gt;
Interface Doc affords considerable implementation flexibility. The print data
might already be in existence when the doc object is constructed. In this
case the objects returned by the doc's methods can be supplied to the doc's
constructor, be stored in the doc ahead of time, and simply be returned when
called for. Alternatively, the print data might not exist yet when the doc
object is constructed. In this case the doc object might provide a "lazy"
implementation that generates the print data representation object (and/or
the print data) only when the Print Job calls for it (when the Print Job
calls the {@link #getPrintData() &lt;CODE&gt;getPrintData()&lt;/CODE&gt;} method).
&lt;P&gt;
There is no restriction on the number of client threads that may be
simultaneously accessing the same doc. Therefore, all implementations of
interface Doc must be designed to be multiple thread safe.
&lt;p&gt;
However there can only be one consumer of the print data obtained from a
Doc.
&lt;p&gt;
If print data is obtained from the client as a stream, by calling Doc's
&lt;code&gt;getReaderForText()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;getStreamForBytes()&lt;/code&gt;
methods, or because the print data source is already an InputStream or
Reader, then the print service should always close these streams for the
client on all job completion conditions. With the following caveat.
If the print data is itself a stream, the service will always close it.
If the print data is otherwise something that can be requested as a stream,
the service will only close the stream if it has obtained the stream before
terminating. That is, just because a print service might request data as
a stream does not mean that it will, with the implications that Doc
implementors which rely on the service to close them should create such
streams only in response to a request from the service.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;HR&gt;
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Doc" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_544729_9513" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_544729_9513"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="Doc" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_544729_9513" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_544729_9513"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>