<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928317563_614332_12004" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928317563_614332_12004"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="DefaultCaret" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_435224_10439" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_435224_10439"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A default implementation of Caret.  The caret is rendered as
a vertical line in the color specified by the CaretColor property
of the associated JTextComponent.  It can blink at the rate specified
by the BlinkRate property.
&lt;p&gt;
This implementation expects two sources of asynchronous notification.
The timer thread fires asynchronously, and causes the caret to simply
repaint the most recent bounding box.  The caret also tracks change
as the document is modified.  Typically this will happen on the
event dispatch thread as a result of some mouse or keyboard event.
The caret behavior on both synchronous and asynchronous documents updates
is controlled by &lt;code&gt;UpdatePolicy&lt;/code&gt; property. The repaint of the
new caret location will occur on the event thread in any case, as calls to
&lt;code&gt;modelToView&lt;/code&gt; are only safe on the event thread.
&lt;p&gt;
The caret acts as a mouse and focus listener on the text component
it has been installed in, and defines the caret semantics based upon
those events.  The listener methods can be reimplemented to change the
semantics.
By default, the first mouse button will be used to set focus and caret
position.  Dragging the mouse pointer with the first mouse button will
sweep out a selection that is contiguous in the model.  If the associated
text component is editable, the caret will become visible when focus
is gained, and invisible when focus is lost.
&lt;p&gt;
The Highlighter bound to the associated text component is used to
render the selection by default.
Selection appearance can be customized by supplying a
painter to use for the highlights.  By default a painter is used that
will render a solid color as specified in the associated text component
in the &lt;code&gt;SelectionColor&lt;/code&gt; property.  This can easily be changed
by reimplementing the
&lt;a href="#getSelectionHighlighter"&gt;getSelectionHighlighter&lt;/a&gt;
method.
&lt;p&gt;
A customized caret appearance can be achieved by reimplementing
the paint method.  If the paint method is changed, the damage method
should also be reimplemented to cause a repaint for the area needed
to render the caret.  The caret extends the Rectangle class which
is used to hold the bounding box for where the caret was last rendered.
This enables the caret to repaint in a thread-safe manner when the
caret moves without making a call to modelToView which is unstable
between model updates and view repair (i.e. the order of delivery
to DocumentListeners is not guaranteed).
&lt;p&gt;
The magic caret position is set to null when the caret position changes.
A timer is used to determine the new location (after the caret change).
When the timer fires, if the magic caret position is still null it is
reset to the current caret position. Any actions that change
the caret position and want the magic caret position to remain the
same, must remember the magic caret position, change the cursor, and
then set the magic caret position to its original value. This has the
benefit that only actions that want the magic caret position to persist
(such as open/down) need to know about it.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt;
Serialized objects of this class will not be compatible with
future Swing releases. The current serialization support is
appropriate for short term storage or RMI between applications running
the same version of Swing.  As of 1.4, support for long term storage
of all JavaBeans&lt;sup&gt;&lt;font size="-2"&gt;TM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
has been added to the &lt;code&gt;java.beans&lt;/code&gt; package.
Please see {@link java.beans.XMLEncoder}.

@author  Timothy Prinzing
@version 1.138 06/24/04
@see     Caret
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="DefaultCaret" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_435224_10439" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_435224_10439"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="DefaultCaret" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_435224_10439" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_435224_10439"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>