<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928318123_1474_12538" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928318123_1474_12538"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="JTable" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_678280_10777" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_678280_10777"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; is used to display and edit regular two-dimensional tables
of cells.
See &lt;a href="http://java.sun.com/docs/books/tutorial/uiswing/components/table.html"&gt;How to Use Tables&lt;/a&gt;
in &lt;em&gt;The Java Tutorial&lt;/em&gt;
for task-oriented documentation and examples of using &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; has many
facilities that make it possible to customize its rendering and editing
but provides defaults for these features so that simple tables can be
set up easily.  For example, to set up a table with 10 rows and 10
columns of numbers:
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
TableModel dataModel = new AbstractTableModel() {
public int getColumnCount() { return 10; }
public int getRowCount() { return 10;}
public Object getValueAt(int row, int col) { return new Integer(row*col); }
};
JTable table = new JTable(dataModel);
JScrollPane scrollpane = new JScrollPane(table);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that if you wish to use a &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; in a standalone
view (outside of a &lt;code&gt;JScrollPane&lt;/code&gt;) and want the header
displayed, you can get it using {@link #getTableHeader} and
display it separately.
&lt;p&gt;
When designing applications that use the &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; it is worth paying
close attention to the data structures that will represent the table's data.
The &lt;code&gt;DefaultTableModel&lt;/code&gt; is a model implementation that
uses a &lt;code&gt;Vector&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;code&gt;Vector&lt;/code&gt;s of &lt;code&gt;Object&lt;/code&gt;s to
store the cell values. As well as copying the data from an
application into the &lt;code&gt;DefaultTableModel&lt;/code&gt;,
it is also possible to wrap the data in the methods of the
&lt;code&gt;TableModel&lt;/code&gt; interface so that the data can be passed to the
&lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; directly, as in the example above. This often results
in more efficient applications because the model is free to choose the
internal representation that best suits the data.
A good rule of thumb for deciding whether to use the &lt;code&gt;AbstractTableModel&lt;/code&gt;
or the &lt;code&gt;DefaultTableModel&lt;/code&gt; is to use the &lt;code&gt;AbstractTableModel&lt;/code&gt;
as the base class for creating subclasses and the &lt;code&gt;DefaultTableModel&lt;/code&gt;
when subclassing is not required.
&lt;p&gt;
The "TableExample" directory in the demo area of the source distribution
gives a number of complete examples of &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; usage,
covering how the &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; can be used to provide an
editable view of data taken from a database and how to modify
the columns in the display to use specialized renderers and editors.
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; uses integers exclusively to refer to both the rows and the columns
of the model that it displays. The &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; simply takes a tabular range of cells
and uses &lt;code&gt;getValueAt(int, int)&lt;/code&gt; to retrieve the
values from the model during painting.
&lt;p&gt;
By default, columns may be rearranged in the &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; so that the
view's columns appear in a different order to the columns in the model.
This does not affect the implementation of the model at all: when the
columns are reordered, the &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; maintains the new order of the columns
internally and converts its column indices before querying the model.
&lt;p&gt;
So, when writing a &lt;code&gt;TableModel&lt;/code&gt;, it is not necessary to listen for column
reordering events as the model will be queried in its own coordinate
system regardless of what is happening in the view.
In the examples area there is a demonstration of a sorting algorithm making
use of exactly this technique to interpose yet another coordinate system
where the order of the rows is changed, rather than the order of the columns.
&lt;p&gt;
J2SE 5 adds methods to &lt;code&gt;JTable&lt;/code&gt; to provide convenient access to some
common printing needs. Simple new {@link #print()} methods allow for quick
and easy addition of printing support to your application. In addition, a new
{@link #getPrintable} method is available for more advanced printing needs.
&lt;p&gt;
As for all &lt;code&gt;JComponent&lt;/code&gt; classes, you can use
{@link InputMap} and {@link ActionMap} to associate an
{@link Action} object with a {@link KeyStroke} and execute the
action under specified conditions.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt;
Serialized objects of this class will not be compatible with
future Swing releases. The current serialization support is
appropriate for short term storage or RMI between applications running
the same version of Swing.  As of 1.4, support for long term storage
of all JavaBeans&lt;sup&gt;&lt;font size="-2"&gt;TM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
has been added to the &lt;code&gt;java.beans&lt;/code&gt; package.
Please see {@link java.beans.XMLEncoder}.


@beaninfo
attribute: isContainer false
description: A component which displays data in a two dimensional grid.

@version 1.238 06/28/04
@author Philip Milne
@author Shannon Hickey (printing support)
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="JTable" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_678280_10777" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_678280_10777"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="JTable" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_678280_10777" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_678280_10777"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>