<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928313477_358937_7486" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928313477_358937_7486"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="Timer" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_358436_8931" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_358436_8931"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A facility for threads to schedule tasks for future execution in a
background thread.  Tasks may be scheduled for one-time execution, or for
repeated execution at regular intervals.

&lt;p&gt;Corresponding to each &lt;tt&gt;Timer&lt;/tt&gt; object is a single background
thread that is used to execute all of the timer's tasks, sequentially.
Timer tasks should complete quickly.  If a timer task takes excessive time
to complete, it "hogs" the timer's task execution thread.  This can, in
turn, delay the execution of subsequent tasks, which may "bunch up" and
execute in rapid succession when (and if) the offending task finally
completes.

&lt;p&gt;After the last live reference to a &lt;tt&gt;Timer&lt;/tt&gt; object goes away
&lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all outstanding tasks have completed execution, the timer's task
execution thread terminates gracefully (and becomes subject to garbage
collection).  However, this can take arbitrarily long to occur.  By
default, the task execution thread does not run as a &lt;i&gt;daemon thread&lt;/i&gt;,
so it is capable of keeping an application from terminating.  If a caller
wants to terminate a timer's task execution thread rapidly, the caller
should invoke the timer's &lt;tt&gt;cancel&lt;/tt&gt; method.

&lt;p&gt;If the timer's task execution thread terminates unexpectedly, for
example, because its &lt;tt&gt;stop&lt;/tt&gt; method is invoked, any further
attempt to schedule a task on the timer will result in an
&lt;tt&gt;IllegalStateException&lt;/tt&gt;, as if the timer's &lt;tt&gt;cancel&lt;/tt&gt;
method had been invoked.

&lt;p&gt;This class is thread-safe: multiple threads can share a single
&lt;tt&gt;Timer&lt;/tt&gt; object without the need for external synchronization.

&lt;p&gt;This class does &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; offer real-time guarantees: it schedules
tasks using the &lt;tt&gt;Object.wait(long)&lt;/tt&gt; method.

&lt;p&gt;Implementation note: This class scales to large numbers of concurrently
scheduled tasks (thousands should present no problem).  Internally,
it uses a binary heap to represent its task queue, so the cost to schedule
a task is O(log n), where n is the number of concurrently scheduled tasks.

&lt;p&gt;Implementation note: All constructors start a timer thread.

@author  Josh Bloch
@version 1.17, 04/12/04
@see     TimerTask
@see     Object#wait(long)
@since   1.3
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Timer" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_358436_8931" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_358436_8931"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="Timer" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_358436_8931" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_358436_8931"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>