<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928306437_624128_4200" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928306437_624128_4200"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="Font" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_23258_7009" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_23258_7009"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; class represents fonts, which are used to
render text in a visible way.
A font provides the information needed to map sequences of
&lt;em&gt;characters&lt;/em&gt; to sequences of &lt;em&gt;glyphs&lt;/em&gt;
and to render sequences of glyphs on &lt;code&gt;Graphics&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;Component&lt;/code&gt; objects.

&lt;h4&gt;Characters and Glyphs&lt;/h4&gt;

A &lt;em&gt;character&lt;/em&gt; is a symbol that represents an item such as a letter,
a digit, or punctuation in an abstract way. For example, &lt;code&gt;'g'&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;font size=-1&gt;LATIN SMALL LETTER G&lt;/font&gt;, is a character.
&lt;p&gt;
A &lt;em&gt;glyph&lt;/em&gt; is a shape used to render a character or a sequence of
characters. In simple writing systems, such as Latin, typically one glyph
represents one character. In general, however, characters and glyphs do not
have one-to-one correspondence. For example, the character '&amp;aacute;'
&lt;font size=-1&gt;LATIN SMALL LETTER A WITH ACUTE&lt;/font&gt;, can be represented by
two glyphs: one for 'a' and one for '&amp;acute;'. On the other hand, the
two-character string "fi" can be represented by a single glyph, an
"fi" ligature. In complex writing systems, such as Arabic or the South
and South-East Asian writing systems, the relationship between characters
and glyphs can be more complicated and involve context-dependent selection
of glyphs as well as glyph reordering.

A font encapsulates the collection of glyphs needed to render a selected set
of characters as well as the tables needed to map sequences of characters to
corresponding sequences of glyphs.

&lt;h4&gt;Physical and Logical Fonts&lt;/h4&gt;

The Java 2 platform distinguishes between two kinds of fonts:
&lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; fonts and &lt;em&gt;logical&lt;/em&gt; fonts.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Physical&lt;/em&gt; fonts are the actual font libraries containing glyph data
and tables to map from character sequences to glyph sequences, using a font
technology such as TrueType or PostScript Type 1.
All implementations of the Java 2 platform must support TrueType fonts;
support for other font technologies is implementation dependent.
Physical fonts may use names such as Helvetica, Palatino, HonMincho, or
any number of other font names.
Typically, each physical font supports only a limited set of writing
systems, for example, only Latin characters or only Japanese and Basic
Latin.
The set of available physical fonts varies between configurations.
Applications that require specific fonts can bundle them and instantiate
them using the {@link #createFont createFont} method.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Logical&lt;/em&gt; fonts are the five font families defined by the Java
platform which must be supported by any Java runtime environment:
Serif, SansSerif, Monospaced, Dialog, and DialogInput.
These logical fonts are not actual font libraries. Instead, the logical
font names are mapped to physical fonts by the Java runtime environment.
The mapping is implementation and usually locale dependent, so the look
and the metrics provided by them vary.
Typically, each logical font name maps to several physical fonts in order to
cover a large range of characters.
&lt;p&gt;
Peered AWT components, such as {@link Label Label} and
{@link TextField TextField}, can only use logical fonts.
&lt;p&gt;
For a discussion of the relative advantages and disadvantages of using
physical or logical fonts, see the
&lt;a href="http://java.sun.com/j2se/corejava/intl/reference/faqs/index.html#desktop-rendering"&gt;Internationalization FAQ&lt;/a&gt;
document.

&lt;h4&gt;Font Faces and Names&lt;/h4&gt;

A &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt;
can have many faces, such as heavy, medium, oblique, gothic and
regular. All of these faces have similar typographic design.
&lt;p&gt;
There are three different names that you can get from a
&lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; object.  The &lt;em&gt;logical font name&lt;/em&gt; is simply the
name that was used to construct the font.
The &lt;em&gt;font face name&lt;/em&gt;, or just &lt;em&gt;font name&lt;/em&gt; for
short, is the name of a particular font face, like Helvetica Bold. The
&lt;em&gt;family name&lt;/em&gt; is the name of the font family that determines the
typographic design across several faces, like Helvetica.
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; class represents an instance of a font face from
a collection of  font faces that are present in the system resources
of the host system.  As examples, Arial Bold and Courier Bold Italic
are font faces.  There can be several &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; objects
associated with a font face, each differing in size, style, transform
and font features.
The {@link GraphicsEnvironment#getAllFonts() getAllFonts} method
of the &lt;code&gt;GraphicsEnvironment&lt;/code&gt; class returns an
array of all font faces available in the system. These font faces are
returned as &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; objects with a size of 1, identity
transform and default font features. These
base fonts can then be used to derive new &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt; objects
with varying sizes, styles, transforms and font features via the
&lt;code&gt;deriveFont&lt;/code&gt; methods in this class.

@version 	1.200, 07/20/04
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Font" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_23258_7009" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_23258_7009"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="Font" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_23258_7009" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_23258_7009"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>