<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_691215_9334" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_691215_9334"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="RequiredModelMBean" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_359671_9332" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_359671_9332"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class is the implementation of a ModelMBean. An appropriate
implementation of a ModelMBean must be shipped with every JMX Agent
and the class must be named RequiredModelMBean.
&lt;P&gt;
Java resources wishing to be manageable instantiate the
RequiredModelMBean using the MBeanServer's createMBean method.
The resource then sets the MBeanInfo and Descriptors for the
RequiredModelMBean instance. The attributes and operations exposed
via the ModelMBeanInfo for the ModelMBean are accessible
from MBeans, connectors/adaptors like other MBeans. Through the
Descriptors, values and methods in the managed application can be
defined and mapped to attributes and operations of the ModelMBean.
This mapping can be defined in an XML formatted file or dynamically and
programmatically at runtime.
&lt;P&gt;
Every RequiredModelMBean which is instantiated in the MBeanServer
becomes manageable:&lt;br&gt;
its attributes and operations become remotely accessible through the
connectors/adaptors connected to that MBeanServer.
&lt;P&gt;
A Java object cannot be registered in the MBeanServer unless it is a
JMX compliant MBean. By instantiating a RequiredModelMBean, resources
are guaranteed that the MBean is valid.

MBeanException and RuntimeOperationsException must be thrown on every
public method.  This allows for wrapping exceptions from distributed
communications (RMI, EJB, etc.)

@since 1.5
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="RequiredModelMBean" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_359671_9332" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_359671_9332"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="RequiredModelMBean" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_359671_9332" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928314929_359671_9332"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>