<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928308990_580262_5667"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="RMIClassLoader" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_658120_8183"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">&lt;code&gt;RMIClassLoader&lt;/code&gt; comprises static methods to support
dynamic class loading with RMI.  Included are methods for loading
classes from a network location (one or more URLs) and obtaining
the location from which an existing class should be loaded by
remote parties.  These methods are used by the RMI runtime when
marshalling and unmarshalling classes contained in the arguments
and return values of remote method calls, and they also may be
invoked directly by applications in order to mimic RMI's dynamic
class loading behavior.

&lt;p&gt;The implementation of the following static methods

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;{@link #loadClass(URL,String)}
&lt;li&gt;{@link #loadClass(String,String)}
&lt;li&gt;{@link #loadClass(String,String,ClassLoader)}
&lt;li&gt;{@link #loadProxyClass(String,String[],ClassLoader)}
&lt;li&gt;{@link #getClassLoader(String)}
&lt;li&gt;{@link #getClassAnnotation(Class)}

&lt;/ul&gt;

is provided by an instance of {@link RMIClassLoaderSpi}, the
service provider interface for those methods.  When one of the
methods is invoked, its behavior is to delegate to a corresponding
method on the service provider instance.  The details of how each
method delegates to the provider instance is described in the
documentation for each particular method.

&lt;p&gt;The service provider instance is chosen as follows:

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If the system property
&lt;code&gt;java.rmi.server.RMIClassLoaderSpi&lt;/code&gt; is defined, then if
its value equals the string &lt;code&gt;"default"&lt;/code&gt;, the provider
instance will be the value returned by an invocation of the {@link
#getDefaultProviderInstance()} method, and for any other value, if
a class named with the value of the property can be loaded by the
system class loader (see {@link ClassLoader#getSystemClassLoader})
and that class is assignable to {@link RMIClassLoaderSpi} and has a
public no-argument constructor, then that constructor will be
invoked to create the provider instance.  If the property is
defined but any other of those conditions are not true, then an
unspecified &lt;code&gt;Error&lt;/code&gt; will be thrown to code that attempts
to use &lt;code&gt;RMIClassLoader&lt;/code&gt;, indicating the failure to
obtain a provider instance.

&lt;li&gt;If a resource named
&lt;code&gt;META-INF/services/java.rmi.server.RMIClassLoaderSpi&lt;/code&gt; is
visible to the system class loader, then the contents of that
resource are interpreted as a provider-configuration file, and the
first class name specified in that file is used as the provider
class name.  If a class with that name can be loaded by the system
class loader and that class is assignable to {@link
RMIClassLoaderSpi} and has a public no-argument constructor, then
that constructor will be invoked to create the provider instance.
If the resource is found but a provider cannot be instantiated as
described, then an unspecified &lt;code&gt;Error&lt;/code&gt; will be thrown to
code that attempts to use &lt;code&gt;RMIClassLoader&lt;/code&gt;, indicating
the failure to obtain a provider instance.

&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, the provider instance will be the value returned by
an invocation of the {@link #getDefaultProviderInstance()} method.

&lt;/ul&gt;

@version	1.40, 04/05/18
@author	Ann Wollrath
@author	Peter Jones
@author	Laird Dornin
@see		RMIClassLoaderSpi
@since	JDK1.1
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="RMIClassLoader" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_658120_8183"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="RMIClassLoader" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_658120_8183"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>