<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928309531_804763_6186"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="SQLData" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_664158_8585"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The interface used for the custom mapping of an SQL user-defined type (UDT) to
a class in the Java programming language. The class object for a class
implementing the &lt;code&gt;SQLData&lt;/code&gt; interface will be entered in the
appropriate &lt;code&gt;Connection&lt;/code&gt; object's type map along with the SQL
name of the UDT for which it is a custom mapping.
&lt;P&gt;
Typically, a &lt;code&gt;SQLData&lt;/code&gt; implementation
will define a field for each attribute of an SQL structured type or a
single field for an SQL &lt;code&gt;DISTINCT&lt;/code&gt; type. When the UDT is
retrieved from a data source with the &lt;code&gt;ResultSet.getObject&lt;/code&gt;
method, it will be mapped as an instance of this class.  A programmer
can operate on this class instance just as on any other object in the
Java programming language and then store any changes made to it by
calling the &lt;code&gt;PreparedStatement.setObject&lt;/code&gt; method,
which will map it back to the SQL type.
&lt;p&gt;
It is expected that the implementation of the class for a custom
mapping will be done by a tool.  In a typical implementation, the
programmer would simply supply the name of the SQL UDT, the name of
the class to which it is being mapped, and the names of the fields to
which each of the attributes of the UDT is to be mapped.  The tool will use
this information to implement the &lt;code&gt;SQLData.readSQL&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;SQLData.writeSQL&lt;/code&gt; methods.  The &lt;code&gt;readSQL&lt;/code&gt; method
calls the appropriate &lt;code&gt;SQLInput&lt;/code&gt; methods to read
each attribute from an &lt;code&gt;SQLInput&lt;/code&gt; object, and the
&lt;code&gt;writeSQL&lt;/code&gt; method calls &lt;code&gt;SQLOutput&lt;/code&gt; methods
to write each attribute back to the data source via an
&lt;code&gt;SQLOutput&lt;/code&gt; object.
&lt;P&gt;
An application programmer will not normally call &lt;code&gt;SQLData&lt;/code&gt; methods
directly, and the &lt;code&gt;SQLInput&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SQLOutput&lt;/code&gt; methods
are called internally by &lt;code&gt;SQLData&lt;/code&gt; methods, not by application code.

@since 1.2
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="SQLData" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_664158_8585"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="SQLData" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_664158_8585"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>