<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928313357_389075_7438"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="RandomAccess" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_6812_8913"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Marker interface used by &lt;tt&gt;List&lt;/tt&gt; implementations to indicate that
they support fast (generally constant time) random access.  The primary
purpose of this interface is to allow generic algorithms to alter their
behavior to provide good performance when applied to either random or
sequential access lists.

&lt;p&gt;The best algorithms for manipulating random access lists (such as
&lt;tt&gt;ArrayList&lt;/tt&gt;) can produce quadratic behavior when applied to
sequential access lists (such as &lt;tt&gt;LinkedList&lt;/tt&gt;).  Generic list
algorithms are encouraged to check whether the given list is an
&lt;tt&gt;instanceof&lt;/tt&gt; this interface before applying an algorithm that would
provide poor performance if it were applied to a sequential access list,
and to alter their behavior if necessary to guarantee acceptable
performance.

&lt;p&gt;It is recognized that the distinction between random and sequential
access is often fuzzy.  For example, some &lt;tt&gt;List&lt;/tt&gt; implementations
provide asymptotically linear access times if they get huge, but constant
access times in practice.  Such a &lt;tt&gt;List&lt;/tt&gt; implementation
should generally implement this interface.  As a rule of thumb, a
&lt;tt&gt;List&lt;/tt&gt; implementation should implement this interface if,
for typical instances of the class, this loop:
&lt;pre&gt;
for (int i=0, n=list.size(); i &lt; n; i++)
list.get(i);
&lt;/pre&gt;
runs faster than this loop:
&lt;pre&gt;
for (Iterator i=list.iterator(); i.hasNext(); )
i.next();
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interface is a member of the
&lt;a href="{@docRoot}/../guide/collections/index.html"&gt;
Java Collections Framework&lt;/a&gt;.

</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="RandomAccess" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_6812_8913"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="RandomAccess" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_6812_8913"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>