<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928317553_849059_11990"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="BoxView" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_76097_10427"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A view that arranges its children into a box shape by tiling
its children along an axis.  The box is somewhat like that
found in TeX where there is alignment of the
children, flexibility of the children is considered, etc.
This is a building block that might be useful to represent
things like a collection of lines, paragraphs,
lists, columns, pages, etc.  The axis along which the children are tiled is
considered the major axis.  The orthoginal axis is the minor axis.
&lt;p&gt;
Layout for each axis is handled separately by the methods
&lt;code&gt;layoutMajorAxis&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;layoutMinorAxis&lt;/code&gt;.
Subclasses can change the layout algorithm by
reimplementing these methods.    These methods will be called
as necessary depending upon whether or not there is cached
layout information and the cache is considered
valid.  These methods are typically called if the given size
along the axis changes, or if &lt;code&gt;layoutChanged&lt;/code&gt; is
called to force an updated layout.  The &lt;code&gt;layoutChanged&lt;/code&gt;
method invalidates cached layout information, if there is any.
The requirements published to the parent view are calculated by
the methods &lt;code&gt;calculateMajorAxisRequirements&lt;/code&gt;
and  &lt;code&gt;calculateMinorAxisRequirements&lt;/code&gt;.
If the layout algorithm is changed, these methods will
likely need to be reimplemented.

@author  Timothy Prinzing
@version 1.61 03/05/04
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="BoxView" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_76097_10427"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="BoxView" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546784_76097_10427"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>