<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315740_787289_10225"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="PrinterResolution" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_936754_9417"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Class PrinterResolution is a printing attribute class that specifies an
exact resolution supported by a printer or to be used for a print job.
This attribute assumes that printers have a small set of device resolutions
at which they can operate rather than a continuum.
&lt;p&gt;
PrinterResolution is used in multiple ways:
&lt;OL TYPE=1&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
When a client searches looking for a printer that supports the client's
desired resolution exactly (no more, no less), the client specifies
an instance of class PrinterResolution indicating the exact resolution the
client wants. Only printers supporting that exact resolution will match the
search.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
When a client needs to print a job using the client's desired resolution
exactly (no more, no less), the client specifies an instance of class
PrinterResolution as an attribute of the Print Job. This will fail if the
Print Job doesn't support that exact resolution, and Fidelity is set to
true.
&lt;/OL&gt;
If a client wants to locate a printer supporting a resolution
greater than some required minimum, then it may be necessary to exclude
this attribute from a lookup request and to directly query the set of
supported resolutions, and specify the one that most closely meets
the client's requirements.
In some cases this may be more simply achieved by specifying a
PrintQuality attribute which often controls resolution.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The information needed to construct an IPP
&lt;CODE&gt;"printer-resolution"&lt;/CODE&gt; attribute can be obtained by calling
methods on the PrinterResolution object. The category name returned by
&lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; gives the IPP attribute name.
&lt;P&gt;

@author  David Mendenhall
@author  Alan Kaminsky
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="PrinterResolution" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_936754_9417"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="PrinterResolution" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546721_936754_9417"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>