<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_107299_6691" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_107299_6691"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="SynchronousQueue" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_422265_6674" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_422265_6674"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A {@linkplain BlockingQueue blocking queue} in which each
&lt;tt&gt;put&lt;/tt&gt; must wait for a &lt;tt&gt;take&lt;/tt&gt;, and vice versa.  A
synchronous queue does not have any internal capacity, not even a
capacity of one. You cannot &lt;tt&gt;peek&lt;/tt&gt; at a synchronous queue
because an element is only present when you try to take it; you
cannot add an element (using any method) unless another thread is
trying to remove it; you cannot iterate as there is nothing to
iterate.  The &lt;em&gt;head&lt;/em&gt; of the queue is the element that the
first queued thread is trying to add to the queue; if there are no
queued threads then no element is being added and the head is
&lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt;.  For purposes of other &lt;tt&gt;Collection&lt;/tt&gt; methods
(for example &lt;tt&gt;contains&lt;/tt&gt;), a &lt;tt&gt;SynchronousQueue&lt;/tt&gt; acts
as an empty collection.  This queue does not permit &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt;
elements.

&lt;p&gt;Synchronous queues are similar to rendezvous channels used in
CSP and Ada. They are well suited for handoff designs, in which an
object running in one thread must sync up with an object running
in another thread in order to hand it some information, event, or
task.

&lt;p&gt; This class supports an optional fairness policy for ordering
waiting producer and consumer threads.  By default, this ordering
is not guaranteed. However, a queue constructed with fairness set
to &lt;tt&gt;true&lt;/tt&gt; grants threads access in FIFO order. Fairness
generally decreases throughput but reduces variability and avoids
starvation.

&lt;p&gt;This class and its iterator implement all of the
&lt;em&gt;optional&lt;/em&gt; methods of the {@link Collection} and {@link
Iterator} interfaces.

&lt;p&gt;This class is a member of the
&lt;a href="{@docRoot}/../guide/collections/index.html"&gt;
Java Collections Framework&lt;/a&gt;.

@since 1.5
@author Doug Lea
@param &lt;E&gt; the type of elements held in this collection
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="SynchronousQueue" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_422265_6674" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_422265_6674"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="SynchronousQueue" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_422265_6674" refid="_10_5_622020d_1132928310242_422265_6674"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>