<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928306667_502841_4255" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928306667_502841_4255"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="KeyEventPostProcessor" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_424939_7061" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_424939_7061"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A KeyEventPostProcessor cooperates with the current KeyboardFocusManager
in the final resolution of all unconsumed KeyEvents. KeyEventPostProcessors
registered with the current KeyboardFocusManager will receive KeyEvents
after the KeyEvents have been dispatched to and handled by their targets.
KeyEvents that would have been otherwise discarded because no Component in
the application currently owns the focus will also be forwarded to
registered KeyEventPostProcessors. This will allow applications to implement
features that require global KeyEvent post-handling, such as menu shortcuts.
&lt;p&gt;
Note that the KeyboardFocusManager itself implements KeyEventPostProcessor.
By default, the current KeyboardFocusManager will be the final
KeyEventPostProcessor in the chain. The current KeyboardFocusManager cannot
be completely deregistered as a KeyEventPostProcessor. However, if a
KeyEventPostProcessor reports that no further post-processing of the
KeyEvent should take place, the AWT will consider the event fully handled
and will take no additional action with regard to the event. (While it is
possible for client code to register the current KeyboardFocusManager as
a KeyEventPostProcessor one or more times, this is usually unnecessary and
not recommended.)

@author David Mendenhall
@version 1.5, 12/19/03

@see KeyboardFocusManager#addKeyEventPostProcessor
@see KeyboardFocusManager#removeKeyEventPostProcessor
@since 1.4
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" mode="s,e" name="KeyEventPostProcessor" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_424939_7061" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_424939_7061"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_1046467249.jpg" name="KeyEventPostProcessor" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_424939_7061" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546581_424939_7061"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>