<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928307388_845769_4684" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928307388_845769_4684"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="RandomAccessFile" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546612_898214_7475" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546612_898214_7475"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Instances of this class support both reading and writing to a
random access file. A random access file behaves like a large
array of bytes stored in the file system. There is a kind of cursor,
or index into the implied array, called the &lt;em&gt;file pointer&lt;/em&gt;;
input operations read bytes starting at the file pointer and advance
the file pointer past the bytes read. If the random access file is
created in read/write mode, then output operations are also available;
output operations write bytes starting at the file pointer and advance
the file pointer past the bytes written. Output operations that write
past the current end of the implied array cause the array to be
extended. The file pointer can be read by the
&lt;code&gt;getFilePointer&lt;/code&gt; method and set by the &lt;code&gt;seek&lt;/code&gt;
method.
&lt;p&gt;
It is generally true of all the reading routines in this class that
if end-of-file is reached before the desired number of bytes has been
read, an &lt;code&gt;EOFException&lt;/code&gt; (which is a kind of
&lt;code&gt;IOException&lt;/code&gt;) is thrown. If any byte cannot be read for
any reason other than end-of-file, an &lt;code&gt;IOException&lt;/code&gt; other
than &lt;code&gt;EOFException&lt;/code&gt; is thrown. In particular, an
&lt;code&gt;IOException&lt;/code&gt; may be thrown if the stream has been closed.

@author  unascribed
@version 1.78, 05/13/04
@since   JDK1.0
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="RandomAccessFile" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546612_898214_7475" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546612_898214_7475"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="RandomAccessFile" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546612_898214_7475" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546612_898214_7475"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>