<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928305986_110993_3914" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928305986_110993_3914"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="BandedSampleModel" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_692826_6749" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_692826_6749"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class represents image data which is stored in a band interleaved
fashion and for
which each sample of a pixel occupies one data element of the DataBuffer.
It subclasses ComponentSampleModel but provides a more efficent
implementation for accessing band interleaved image data than is provided
by ComponentSampleModel.  This class should typically be used when working
with images which store sample data for each band in a different bank of the
DataBuffer. Accessor methods are provided so that image data can be
manipulated directly. Pixel stride is the number of
data array elements between two samples for the same band on the same
scanline. The pixel stride for a BandedSampleModel is one.
Scanline stride is the number of data array elements between
a given sample and the corresponding sample in the same column of the next
scanline.  Band offsets denote the number
of data array elements from the first data array element of the bank
of the DataBuffer holding each band to the first sample of the band.
The bands are numbered from 0 to N-1.
Bank indices denote the correspondence between a bank of the data buffer
and a band of image data.  This class supports
{@link DataBuffer#TYPE_BYTE TYPE_BYTE},
{@link DataBuffer#TYPE_USHORT TYPE_USHORT},
{@link DataBuffer#TYPE_SHORT TYPE_SHORT},
{@link DataBuffer#TYPE_INT TYPE_INT},
{@link DataBuffer#TYPE_FLOAT TYPE_FLOAT}, and
{@link DataBuffer#TYPE_DOUBLE TYPE_DOUBLE} datatypes
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="BandedSampleModel" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_692826_6749" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_692826_6749"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="BandedSampleModel" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_692826_6749" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_692826_6749"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>