<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928315760_613118_10247"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="Sides" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_935844_9439"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">Class Sides is a printing attribute class, an enumeration, that specifies
how print-stream pages are to be imposed upon the sides of an instance of a
selected medium, i.e., an impression.
&lt;P&gt;
The effect of a Sides attribute on a multidoc print job (a job with multiple
documents) depends on whether all the docs have the same sides values
specified or whether different docs have different sides values specified,
and on the (perhaps defaulted) value of the {@link MultipleDocumentHandling
MultipleDocumentHandling} attribute.
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
If all the docs have the same sides value &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt; specified, then any value
of {@link MultipleDocumentHandling MultipleDocumentHandling} makes sense,
and the printer's processing depends on the {@link MultipleDocumentHandling
MultipleDocumentHandling} value:
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SINGLE_DOCUMENT -- All the input docs will be combined together into one
output document. Each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt; impressions from
the output document.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SINGLE_DOCUMENT_NEW_SHEET -- All the input docs will be combined together
into one output document. Each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt;
impressions from the output document. However, the first impression of each
input doc will always start on a new media sheet; this means the last media
sheet of an input doc may have only one impression on it.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SEPARATE_DOCUMENTS_UNCOLLATED_COPIES -- The input docs will remain separate.
Each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt; impressions from the input doc.
Since the input docs are separate, the first impression of each input doc
will always start on a new media sheet; this means the last media sheet of
an input doc may have only one impression on it.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SEPARATE_DOCUMENTS_COLLATED_COPIES -- The input docs will remain separate.
Each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt; impressions from the input doc.
Since the input docs are separate, the first impression of each input doc
will always start on a new media sheet; this means the last media sheet of
an input doc may have only one impression on it.
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SINGLE_DOCUMENT -- All the input docs will be combined together into one
output document. Each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;SUB&gt;i&lt;/SUB&gt;&lt;/I&gt;
impressions from the output document, where &lt;I&gt;i&lt;/I&gt; is the number of the
input doc corresponding to that point in the output document. When the next
input doc has a different sides value from the previous input doc, the first
print-stream page of the next input doc goes at the start of the next media
sheet, possibly leaving only one impression on the previous media sheet.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SINGLE_DOCUMENT_NEW_SHEET -- All the input docs will be combined together
into one output document. Each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;/I&gt;
impressions from the output document. However, the first impression of each
input doc will always start on a new media sheet; this means the last
impression of an input doc may have only one impression on it.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SEPARATE_DOCUMENTS_UNCOLLATED_COPIES -- The input docs will remain separate.
For input doc &lt;I&gt;i,&lt;/I&gt; each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;SUB&gt;i&lt;/SUB&gt;&lt;/I&gt;
impressions from the input doc. Since the input docs are separate, the first
impression of each input doc will always start on a new media sheet; this
means the last media sheet of an input doc may have only one impression on
it.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;
SEPARATE_DOCUMENTS_COLLATED_COPIES -- The input docs will remain separate.
For input doc &lt;I&gt;i,&lt;/I&gt; each media sheet will consist of &lt;I&gt;n&lt;SUB&gt;i&lt;/SUB&gt;&lt;/I&gt;
impressions from the input doc. Since the input docs are separate, the first
impression of each input doc will always start on a new media sheet; this
means the last media sheet of an input doc may have only one impression on
it.
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;IPP Compatibility:&lt;/B&gt; The category name returned by
&lt;CODE&gt;getName()&lt;/CODE&gt; is the IPP attribute name.  The enumeration's
integer value is the IPP enum value.  The &lt;code&gt;toString()&lt;/code&gt; method
returns the IPP string representation of the attribute value.
&lt;P&gt;

@author  Alan Kaminsky
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Sides" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_935844_9439"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="Sides" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546737_935844_9439"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>