<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928309301_962800_5982"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="Certificate" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_479921_8433"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">&lt;p&gt;This is an interface of abstract methods for managing a
variety of identity certificates.
An identity certificate is a guarantee by a principal that
a public key is that of another principal.  (A principal represents
an entity such as an individual user, a group, or a corporation.)

&lt;p&gt;In particular, this interface is intended to be a common
abstraction for constructs that have different formats but
important common uses.  For example, different types of
certificates, such as X.509 certificates and PGP certificates,
share general certificate functionality (the need to encode and
decode certificates) and some types of information, such as a
public key, the principal whose key it is, and the guarantor
guaranteeing that the public key is that of the specified
principal. So an implementation of X.509 certificates and an
implementation of PGP certificates can both utilize the Certificate
interface, even though their formats and additional types and
amounts of information stored are different.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Important&lt;/b&gt;: This interface is useful for cataloging and
grouping objects sharing certain common uses. It does not have any
semantics of its own. In particular, a Certificate object does not
make any statement as to the &lt;i&gt;validity&lt;/i&gt; of the binding. It is
the duty of the application implementing this interface to verify
the certificate and satisfy itself of its validity.

@version 	1.37, 05/18/04
@author Benjamin Renaud
@deprecated A new certificate handling package is created in the Java 2 platform.
This Certificate interface is entirely deprecated and
is here to allow for a smooth transition to the new
package.
@see java.security.cert.Certificate
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Certificate" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_479921_8433"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="Certificate" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546674_479921_8433"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>