<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928313327_716766_7385" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928313327_716766_7385"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="Locale" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_180147_8891" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_180147_8891"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; object represents a specific geographical, political,
or cultural region. An operation that requires a &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; to perform
its task is called &lt;em&gt;locale-sensitive&lt;/em&gt; and uses the &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt;
to tailor information for the user. For example, displaying a number
is a locale-sensitive operation--the number should be formatted
according to the customs/conventions of the user's native country,
region, or culture.

&lt;P&gt;
Create a &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; object using the constructors in this class:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Locale(String language)
Locale(String language, String country)
Locale(String language, String country, String variant)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The language argument is a valid &lt;STRONG&gt;ISO Language Code.&lt;/STRONG&gt;
These codes are the lower-case, two-letter codes as defined by ISO-639.
You can find a full list of these codes at a number of sites, such as:
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;a href ="http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/englangn.html"&gt;
&lt;code&gt;http://www.loc.gov/standards/iso639-2/englangn.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
The country argument is a valid &lt;STRONG&gt;ISO Country Code.&lt;/STRONG&gt; These
codes are the upper-case, two-letter codes as defined by ISO-3166.
You can find a full list of these codes at a number of sites, such as:
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.iso.ch/iso/en/prods-services/iso3166ma/02iso-3166-code-lists/list-en1.html"&gt;
&lt;code&gt;http://www.iso.ch/iso/en/prods-services/iso3166ma/02iso-3166-code-lists/list-en1.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
The variant argument is a vendor or browser-specific code.
For example, use WIN for Windows, MAC for Macintosh, and POSIX for POSIX.
Where there are two variants, separate them with an underscore, and
put the most important one first. For example, a Traditional Spanish collation
might construct a locale with parameters for language, country and variant as:
"es", "ES", "Traditional_WIN".

&lt;P&gt;
Because a &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; object is just an identifier for a region,
no validity check is performed when you construct a &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt;.
If you want to see whether particular resources are available for the
&lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; you construct, you must query those resources. For
example, ask the &lt;code&gt;NumberFormat&lt;/code&gt; for the locales it supports
using its &lt;code&gt;getAvailableLocales&lt;/code&gt; method.
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Note:&lt;/STRONG&gt; When you ask for a resource for a particular
locale, you get back the best available match, not necessarily
precisely what you asked for. For more information, look at
{@link ResourceBundle}.

&lt;P&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; class provides a number of convenient constants
that you can use to create &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; objects for commonly used
locales. For example, the following creates a &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; object
for the United States:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Locale.US
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;P&gt;
Once you've created a &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; you can query it for information about
itself. Use &lt;code&gt;getCountry&lt;/code&gt; to get the ISO Country Code and
&lt;code&gt;getLanguage&lt;/code&gt; to get the ISO Language Code. You can
use &lt;code&gt;getDisplayCountry&lt;/code&gt; to get the
name of the country suitable for displaying to the user. Similarly,
you can use &lt;code&gt;getDisplayLanguage&lt;/code&gt; to get the name of
the language suitable for displaying to the user. Interestingly,
the &lt;code&gt;getDisplayXXX&lt;/code&gt; methods are themselves locale-sensitive
and have two versions: one that uses the default locale and one
that uses the locale specified as an argument.

&lt;P&gt;
The Java 2 platform provides a number of classes that perform locale-sensitive
operations. For example, the &lt;code&gt;NumberFormat&lt;/code&gt; class formats
numbers, currency, or percentages in a locale-sensitive manner. Classes
such as &lt;code&gt;NumberFormat&lt;/code&gt; have a number of convenience methods
for creating a default object of that type. For example, the
&lt;code&gt;NumberFormat&lt;/code&gt; class provides these three convenience methods
for creating a default &lt;code&gt;NumberFormat&lt;/code&gt; object:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
NumberFormat.getInstance()
NumberFormat.getCurrencyInstance()
NumberFormat.getPercentInstance()
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
These methods have two variants; one with an explicit locale
and one without; the latter using the default locale.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
NumberFormat.getInstance(myLocale)
NumberFormat.getCurrencyInstance(myLocale)
NumberFormat.getPercentInstance(myLocale)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
A &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt; is the mechanism for identifying the kind of object
(&lt;code&gt;NumberFormat&lt;/code&gt;) that you would like to get. The locale is
&lt;STRONG&gt;just&lt;/STRONG&gt; a mechanism for identifying objects,
&lt;STRONG&gt;not&lt;/STRONG&gt; a container for the objects themselves.

@see         ResourceBundle
@see         java.text.Format
@see         java.text.NumberFormat
@see         java.text.Collator
@author      Mark Davis
@since       1.1
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Locale" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_180147_8891" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_180147_8891"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="Locale" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_180147_8891" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_180147_8891"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>