<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928309351_918135_6061" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928309351_918135_6061"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="KeyStore" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_682450_8477" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_682450_8477"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class represents a storage facility for cryptographic
keys and certificates.

&lt;p&gt; A &lt;code&gt;KeyStore&lt;/code&gt; manages different types of entries.
Each type of entry implements the &lt;code&gt;KeyStore.Entry&lt;/code&gt; interface.
Three basic &lt;code&gt;KeyStore.Entry&lt;/code&gt; implementations are provided:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;KeyStore.PrivateKeyEntry&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This type of entry holds a cryptographic &lt;code&gt;PrivateKey&lt;/code&gt;,
which is optionally stored in a protected format to prevent
unauthorized access.  It is also accompanied by a certificate chain
for the corresponding public key.

&lt;p&gt; Private keys and certificate chains are used by a given entity for
self-authentication. Applications for this authentication include software
distribution organizations which sign JAR files as part of releasing
and/or licensing software.

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;KeyStore.SecretKeyEntry&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This type of entry holds a cryptographic &lt;code&gt;SecretKey&lt;/code&gt;,
which is optionally stored in a protected format to prevent
unauthorized access.

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;KeyStore.TrustedCertificateEntry&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This type of entry contains a single public key &lt;code&gt;Certificate&lt;/code&gt;
belonging to another party. It is called a &lt;i&gt;trusted certificate&lt;/i&gt;
because the keystore owner trusts that the public key in the certificate
indeed belongs to the identity identified by the &lt;i&gt;subject&lt;/i&gt; (owner)
of the certificate.

&lt;p&gt;This type of entry can be used to authenticate other parties.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Each entry in a keystore is identified by an "alias" string. In the
case of private keys and their associated certificate chains, these strings
distinguish among the different ways in which the entity may authenticate
itself. For example, the entity may authenticate itself using different
certificate authorities, or using different public key algorithms.

&lt;p&gt; Whether keystores are persistent, and the mechanisms used by the
keystore if it is persistent, are not specified here. This allows
use of a variety of techniques for protecting sensitive (e.g., private or
secret) keys. Smart cards or other integrated cryptographic engines
(SafeKeyper) are one option, and simpler mechanisms such as files may also
be used (in a variety of formats).

&lt;p&gt; Typical ways to request a KeyStore object include
relying on the default type and providing a specific keystore type.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To rely on the default type:
&lt;pre&gt;
KeyStore ks = KeyStore.getInstance(KeyStore.getDefaultType());
&lt;/pre&gt;
The system will return a keystore implementation for the default type.
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To provide a specific keystore type:
&lt;pre&gt;
KeyStore ks = KeyStore.getInstance("JKS");
&lt;/pre&gt;
The system will return the most preferred implementation of the
specified keystore type available in the environment. &lt;p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Before a keystore can be accessed, it must be
{@link #load(java.io.InputStream, char[]) loaded}.
&lt;pre&gt;
KeyStore ks = KeyStore.getInstance(KeyStore.getDefaultType());

get user password and file input stream
char[] password = getPassword();
java.io.FileInputStream fis =
new java.io.FileInputStream("keyStoreName");
ks.load(fis, password);
fis.close();
&lt;/pre&gt;

To create an empty keystore using the above &lt;code&gt;load&lt;/code&gt; method,
pass &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; as the &lt;code&gt;InputStream&lt;/code&gt; argument.

&lt;p&gt; Once the keystore has been loaded, it is possible
to read existing entries from the keystore, or to write new entries
into the keystore:
&lt;pre&gt;
get my private key
KeyStore.PrivateKeyEntry pkEntry = (KeyStore.PrivateKeyEntry)
ks.getEntry("privateKeyAlias", password);
PrivateKey myPrivateKey = pkEntry.getPrivateKey();

save my secret key
javax.crypto.SecretKey mySecretKey;
KeyStore.SecretKeyEntry skEntry =
new KeyStore.SecretKeyEntry(mySecretKey);
ks.setEntry("secretKeyAlias", skEntry, password);

store away the keystore
java.io.FileOutputStream fos =
new java.io.FileOutputStream("newKeyStoreName");
ks.store(fos, password);
fos.close();
&lt;/pre&gt;

Note that although the same password may be used to
load the keystore, to protect the private key entry,
to protect the secret key entry, and to store the keystore
(as is shown in the sample code above),
different passwords or other protection parameters
may also be used.

@author Jan Luehe

@version 1.42, 06/28/04

@see java.security.PrivateKey
@see javax.crypto.SecretKey
@see java.security.cert.Certificate

@since 1.2
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" mode="s,e" name="KeyStore" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_682450_8477" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_682450_8477"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_555864569.jpg" name="KeyStore" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_682450_8477" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546690_682450_8477"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>