<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_841774062.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928314749_139678_9102" refElementId="_10_5_622020d_1132928314749_139678_9102"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" name="AccessibleContext" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_746063_8959" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_746063_8959"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">AccessibleContext represents the minimum information all accessible objects
return.  This information includes the accessible name, description, role,
and state of the object, as well as information about its parent and
children.  AccessibleContext also contains methods for
obtaining more specific accessibility information about a component.
If the component supports them, these methods will return an object that
implements one or more of the following interfaces:
&lt;P&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;{@link AccessibleAction} - the object can perform one or more actions.
This interface provides the standard mechanism for an assistive
technology to determine what those actions are and tell the object
to perform them.  Any object that can be manipulated should
support this interface.
&lt;li&gt;{@link AccessibleComponent} - the object has a graphical representation.
This interface provides the standard mechanism for an assistive
technology to determine and set the graphical representation of the
object.  Any object that is rendered on the screen should support
this interface.
&lt;li&gt;{@link  AccessibleSelection} - the object allows its children to be
selected.  This interface provides the standard mechanism for an
assistive technology to determine the currently selected children of the object
as well as modify its selection set.  Any object that has children
that can be selected should support this interface.
&lt;li&gt;{@link AccessibleText} - the object presents editable textual information
on the display.  This interface provides the standard mechanism for
an assistive technology to access that text via its content, attributes,
and spatial location.  Any object that contains editable text should
support this interface.
&lt;li&gt;{@link AccessibleValue} - the object supports a numerical value.  This
interface provides the standard mechanism for an assistive technology
to determine and set the current value of the object, as well as obtain its
minimum and maximum values.  Any object that supports a numerical value
should support this interface.&lt;/ul&gt;


@beaninfo
attribute: isContainer false
description: Minimal information that all accessible objects return

@version     1.43 04/02/04
@author	Peter Korn
@author      Hans Muller
@author      Willie Walker
@author      Lynn Monsanto
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" mode="s,e" name="AccessibleContext" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_746063_8959" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_746063_8959"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_795627831.jpg" name="AccessibleContext" refElementId="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_746063_8959" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_746063_8959"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>