<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928318183_700993_12575"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="KeyboardManager" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_992059_10797"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The KeyboardManager class is used to help dispatch keyboard actions for the
WHEN_IN_FOCUSED_WINDOW style actions.  Actions with other conditions are handled
directly in JComponent.

Here's a description of the symantics of how keyboard dispatching should work
atleast as I understand it.

KeyEvents are dispatched to the focused component.  The focus manager gets first
crack at processing this event.  If the focus manager doesn't want it, then
the JComponent calls super.processKeyEvent() this allows listeners a chance
to process the event.

If none of the listeners "consumes" the event then the keybindings get a shot.
This is where things start to get interesting.  First, KeyStokes defined with the
WHEN_FOCUSED condition get a chance.  If none of these want the event, then the component
walks though it's parents looked for actions of type WHEN_ANCESTOR_OF_FOCUSED_COMPONENT.

If no one has taken it yet, then it winds up here.  We then look for components registered
for WHEN_IN_FOCUSED_WINDOW events and fire to them.  Note that if none of those are found
then we pass the event to the menubars and let them have a crack at it.  They're handled differently.

Lastly, we check if we're looking at an internal frame.  If we are and no one wanted the event
then we move up to the InternalFrame's creator and see if anyone wants the event (and so on and so on).


@see InputMap
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="KeyboardManager" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_992059_10797"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="KeyboardManager" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546799_992059_10797"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>