<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928313477_882010_7477"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><interface classType="Interface" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="SortedSet" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_591756_8925"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A set that further guarantees that its iterator will traverse the set in
ascending element order, sorted according to the &lt;i&gt;natural ordering&lt;/i&gt; of
its elements (see Comparable), or by a Comparator provided at sorted set
creation time.  Several additional operations are provided to take
advantage of the ordering.  (This interface is the set analogue of
SortedMap.)&lt;p&gt;

All elements inserted into an sorted set must implement the Comparable
interface (or be accepted by the specified Comparator).  Furthermore, all
such elements must be &lt;i&gt;mutually comparable&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;tt&gt;e1.compareTo(e2)&lt;/tt&gt;
(or &lt;tt&gt;comparator.compare(e1, e2)&lt;/tt&gt;) must not throw a
&lt;tt&gt;ClassCastException&lt;/tt&gt; for any elements &lt;tt&gt;e1&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;e2&lt;/tt&gt; in
the sorted set.  Attempts to violate this restriction will cause the
offending method or constructor invocation to throw a
&lt;tt&gt;ClassCastException&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;p&gt;

Note that the ordering maintained by a sorted set (whether or not an
explicit comparator is provided) must be &lt;i&gt;consistent with equals&lt;/i&gt; if
the sorted set is to correctly implement the &lt;tt&gt;Set&lt;/tt&gt; interface.  (See
the &lt;tt&gt;Comparable&lt;/tt&gt; interface or &lt;tt&gt;Comparator&lt;/tt&gt; interface for a
precise definition of &lt;i&gt;consistent with equals&lt;/i&gt;.)  This is so because
the &lt;tt&gt;Set&lt;/tt&gt; interface is defined in terms of the &lt;tt&gt;equals&lt;/tt&gt;
operation, but a sorted set performs all element comparisons using its
&lt;tt&gt;compareTo&lt;/tt&gt; (or &lt;tt&gt;compare&lt;/tt&gt;) method, so two elements that are
deemed equal by this method are, from the standpoint of the sorted set,
equal.  The behavior of a sorted set &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; well-defined even if its
ordering is inconsistent with equals; it just fails to obey the general
contract of the &lt;tt&gt;Set&lt;/tt&gt; interface.&lt;p&gt;

All general-purpose sorted set implementation classes should provide four
"standard" constructors: 1) A void (no arguments) constructor, which
creates an empty sorted set sorted according to the &lt;i&gt;natural order&lt;/i&gt; of
its elements.  2) A constructor with a single argument of type
&lt;tt&gt;Comparator&lt;/tt&gt;, which creates an empty sorted set sorted according to
the specified comparator.  3) A constructor with a single argument of type
&lt;tt&gt;Collection&lt;/tt&gt;, which creates a new sorted set with the same elements
as its argument, sorted according to the elements' natural ordering.  4) A
constructor with a single argument of type &lt;tt&gt;SortedSet&lt;/tt&gt;, which
creates a new sorted set with the same elements and the same ordering as
the input sorted set.  There is no way to enforce this recommendation (as
interfaces cannot contain constructors) but the JDK implementation (the
&lt;tt&gt;TreeSet&lt;/tt&gt; class) complies.&lt;p&gt;

This interface is a member of the
&lt;a href="{@docRoot}/../guide/collections/index.html"&gt;
Java Collections Framework&lt;/a&gt;.

@author  Josh Bloch
@version 1.24, 06/28/04
@see Set
@see TreeSet
@see SortedMap
@see Collection
@see Comparable
@see Comparator
@see java.lang.ClassCastException
@since 1.2
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Interface" humanName="Owner" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" mode="s,e" name="SortedSet" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_591756_8925"/><owningElement classType="Interface" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Interface" icon="index_files/icon_interface_118881143.jpg" name="SortedSet" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_591756_8925"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>