<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928313226_723712_7292"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="Hashtable" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_512249_8873"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">This class implements a hashtable, which maps keys to values. Any
non-&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; object can be used as a key or as a value. &lt;p&gt;

To successfully store and retrieve objects from a hashtable, the
objects used as keys must implement the &lt;code&gt;hashCode&lt;/code&gt;
method and the &lt;code&gt;equals&lt;/code&gt; method. &lt;p&gt;

An instance of &lt;code&gt;Hashtable&lt;/code&gt; has two parameters that affect its
performance: &lt;i&gt;initial capacity&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;load factor&lt;/i&gt;.  The
&lt;i&gt;capacity&lt;/i&gt; is the number of &lt;i&gt;buckets&lt;/i&gt; in the hash table, and the
&lt;i&gt;initial capacity&lt;/i&gt; is simply the capacity at the time the hash table
is created.  Note that the hash table is &lt;i&gt;open&lt;/i&gt;: in the case of a "hash
collision", a single bucket stores multiple entries, which must be searched
sequentially.  The &lt;i&gt;load factor&lt;/i&gt; is a measure of how full the hash
table is allowed to get before its capacity is automatically increased.
The initial capacity and load factor parameters are merely hints to
the implementation.  The exact details as to when and whether the rehash
method is invoked are implementation-dependent.&lt;p&gt;

Generally, the default load factor (.75) offers a good tradeoff between
time and space costs.  Higher values decrease the space overhead but
increase the time cost to look up an entry (which is reflected in most
&lt;tt&gt;Hashtable&lt;/tt&gt; operations, including &lt;tt&gt;get&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;put&lt;/tt&gt;).&lt;p&gt;

The initial capacity controls a tradeoff between wasted space and the
need for &lt;code&gt;rehash&lt;/code&gt; operations, which are time-consuming.
No &lt;code&gt;rehash&lt;/code&gt; operations will &lt;i&gt;ever&lt;/i&gt; occur if the initial
capacity is greater than the maximum number of entries the
&lt;tt&gt;Hashtable&lt;/tt&gt; will contain divided by its load factor.  However,
setting the initial capacity too high can waste space.&lt;p&gt;

If many entries are to be made into a &lt;code&gt;Hashtable&lt;/code&gt;,
creating it with a sufficiently large capacity may allow the
entries to be inserted more efficiently than letting it perform
automatic rehashing as needed to grow the table. &lt;p&gt;

This example creates a hashtable of numbers. It uses the names of
the numbers as keys:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Hashtable numbers = new Hashtable();
numbers.put("one", new Integer(1));
numbers.put("two", new Integer(2));
numbers.put("three", new Integer(3));
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To retrieve a number, use the following code:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
Integer n = (Integer)numbers.get("two");
if (n != null) {
System.out.println("two = " + n);
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As of the Java 2 platform v1.2, this class has been retrofitted to
implement Map, so that it becomes a part of Java's collection framework.
Unlike the new collection implementations, Hashtable is synchronized.&lt;p&gt;

The Iterators returned by the iterator and listIterator methods
of the Collections returned by all of Hashtable's "collection view methods"
are &lt;em&gt;fail-fast&lt;/em&gt;: if the Hashtable is structurally modified
at any time after the Iterator is created, in any way except through the
Iterator's own remove or add methods, the Iterator will throw a
ConcurrentModificationException.  Thus, in the face of concurrent
modification, the Iterator fails quickly and cleanly, rather than risking
arbitrary, non-deterministic behavior at an undetermined time in the future.
The Enumerations returned by Hashtable's keys and values methods are
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; fail-fast.

&lt;p&gt;Note that the fail-fast behavior of an iterator cannot be guaranteed
as it is, generally speaking, impossible to make any hard guarantees in the
presence of unsynchronized concurrent modification.  Fail-fast iterators
throw &lt;tt&gt;ConcurrentModificationException&lt;/tt&gt; on a best-effort basis.
Therefore, it would be wrong to write a program that depended on this
exception for its correctness: &lt;i&gt;the fail-fast behavior of iterators
should be used only to detect bugs.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;

This class is a member of the
&lt;a href="{@docRoot}/../guide/collections/index.html"&gt;
Java Collections Framework&lt;/a&gt;.

@author  Arthur van Hoff
@author  Josh Bloch
@author  Neal Gafter
@version 1.105, 12/19/03
@see     Object#equals(java.lang.Object)
@see     Object#hashCode()
@see     Hashtable#rehash()
@see     Collection
@see	    Map
@see	    HashMap
@see	    TreeMap
@since JDK1.0
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" mode="s,e" name="Hashtable" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_512249_8873"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_1555793073.jpg" name="Hashtable" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_512249_8873"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>