<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928305816_236988_3779"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" name="GlyphVector" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_996054_6629"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">A &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; object is a collection of glyphs
containing geometric information for the placement of each glyph
in a transformed coordinate space which corresponds to the
device on which the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; is ultimately
displayed.
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; does not attempt any interpretation of
the sequence of glyphs it contains.  Relationships between adjacent
glyphs in sequence are solely used to determine the placement of
the glyphs in the visual coordinate space.
&lt;p&gt;
Instances of &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; are created by a {@link Font}.
&lt;p&gt;
In a text processing application that can cache intermediate
representations of text, creation and subsequent caching of a
&lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; for use during rendering is the fastest
method to present the visual representation of characters to a user.
&lt;p&gt;
A &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; is associated with exactly one
&lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt;, and can provide data useful only in relation to
this &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt;.  In addition, metrics obtained from a
&lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; are not generally geometrically scaleable
since the pixelization and spacing are dependent on grid-fitting
algorithms within a &lt;code&gt;Font&lt;/code&gt;.  To facilitate accurate
measurement of a &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; and its component
glyphs, you must specify a scaling transform, anti-alias mode, and
fractional metrics mode when creating the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.
These characteristics can be derived from the destination device.
&lt;p&gt;
For each glyph in the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;, you can obtain:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the position of the glyph
&lt;li&gt;the transform associated with the glyph
&lt;li&gt;the metrics of the glyph in the context of the
&lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.  The metrics of the glyph may be
different under different transforms, application specified
rendering hints, and the specific instance of the glyph within
the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Altering the data used to create the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; does not
alter the state of the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;
Methods are provided to adjust the positions of the glyphs
within the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.  These methods are most
appropriate for applications that are performing justification
operations for the presentation of the glyphs.
&lt;p&gt;
Methods are provided to transform individual glyphs within the
&lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.  These methods are primarily useful for
special effects.
&lt;p&gt;
Methods are provided to return both the visual, logical, and pixel bounds
of the entire &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt; or of individual glyphs within
the &lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;
Methods are provided to return a {@link Shape} for the
&lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;, and for individual glyphs within the
&lt;code&gt;GlyphVector&lt;/code&gt;.
@see Font
@see GlyphMetrics
@see TextLayout
@version 19 Mar 1998
@author Charlton Innovations, Inc.
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" mode="s,e" name="GlyphVector" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_996054_6629"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" name="GlyphVector" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546565_996054_6629"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>