<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><magicdraw><comment classType="Comment" humanType="Comment" icon="index_files/icon_comment_2051026490.jpg" id="_10_5_622020d_1132928314809_258508_9205"><annotatedElement humanName="Annotated Element" mode="s,e"><class classType="Class" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" name="ImageWriterSpi" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_248093_9051"/></annotatedElement><body humanName="Body" mode="s,e">The service provider interface (SPI) for &lt;code&gt;ImageWriter&lt;/code&gt;s.
For more information on service provider classes, see the class comment
for the &lt;code&gt;IIORegistry&lt;/code&gt; class.

&lt;p&gt; Each &lt;code&gt;ImageWriterSpi&lt;/code&gt; provides several types of information
about the &lt;code&gt;ImageWriter&lt;/code&gt; class with which it is associated.

&lt;p&gt; The name of the vendor who defined the SPI class and a
brief description of the class are available via the
&lt;code&gt;getVendorName&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;getDescription&lt;/code&gt;,
and &lt;code&gt;getVersion&lt;/code&gt; methods.
These methods may be internationalized to provide locale-specific
output.  These methods are intended mainly to provide short,
human-writable information that might be used to organize a pop-up
menu or other list.

&lt;p&gt; Lists of format names, file suffixes, and MIME types associated
with the service may be obtained by means of the
&lt;code&gt;getFormatNames&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;getFileSuffixes&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;getMIMEType&lt;/code&gt; methods.  These methods may be used to
identify candidate &lt;code&gt;ImageWriter&lt;/code&gt;s for writing a
particular file or stream based on manual format selection, file
naming, or MIME associations.

&lt;p&gt; A more reliable way to determine which &lt;code&gt;ImageWriter&lt;/code&gt;s
are likely to be able to parse a particular data stream is provided
by the &lt;code&gt;canEncodeImage&lt;/code&gt; method.  This methods allows the
service provider to inspect the actual image contents.

&lt;p&gt; Finally, an instance of the &lt;code&gt;ImageWriter&lt;/code&gt; class
associated with this service provider may be obtained by calling
the &lt;code&gt;createWriterInstance&lt;/code&gt; method.  Any heavyweight
initialization, such as the loading of native libraries or creation
of large tables, should be deferred at least until the first
invocation of this method.

@see IIORegistry
@see javax.imageio.ImageTypeSpecifier
@see javax.imageio.ImageWriter

@version 0.5
</body><documentation humanName="Documentation"/><owner classType="Class" humanName="Owner" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" mode="s,e" name="ImageWriterSpi" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_248093_9051"/><owningElement classType="Class" humanName="Owning Element" humanType="Class" icon="index_files/icon_class_303957224.jpg" name="ImageWriterSpi" refid="_9_5_f720368_1110473546706_248093_9051"/><TO_DO humanName="To Do" mode="s,e"/></comment></magicdraw>